This file is a merged representation of a subset of the codebase, containing specifically included files, combined into a single document by Repomix.

<file_summary>
This section contains a summary of this file.

<purpose>
This file contains a packed representation of a subset of the repository's contents that is considered the most important context.
It is designed to be easily consumable by AI systems for analysis, code review,
or other automated processes.
</purpose>

<file_format>
The content is organized as follows:
1. This summary section
2. Repository information
3. Directory structure
4. Repository files (if enabled)
5. Multiple file entries, each consisting of:
  - File path as an attribute
  - Full contents of the file
</file_format>

<usage_guidelines>
- This file should be treated as read-only. Any changes should be made to the
  original repository files, not this packed version.
- When processing this file, use the file path to distinguish
  between different files in the repository.
- Be aware that this file may contain sensitive information. Handle it with
  the same level of security as you would the original repository.
</usage_guidelines>

<notes>
- Some files may have been excluded based on .gitignore rules and Repomix's configuration
- Binary files are not included in this packed representation. Please refer to the Repository Structure section for a complete list of file paths, including binary files
- Only files matching these patterns are included: docs/sin-rfp/source/INSTRUCTIONS.md, docs/sin-rfp/response/**/final.md, docs/sin-rfp/response/**/update-notes.md, docs/sin-rfp/source/VIASPORT-PROVIDED-viasport-sin-rfp.md, docs/sin-rfp/source/VIASPORT-PROVIDED-system-requirements-addendum.md, docs/sin-rfp/source/example-rfp-sample.md, docs/sin-rfp/source/initial-template-rfp-response.md
- Files matching patterns in .gitignore are excluded
- Files matching default ignore patterns are excluded
- Files are sorted by Git change count (files with more changes are at the bottom)
</notes>

</file_summary>

<directory_structure>
docs/
  sin-rfp/
    response/
      01-executive-summary/
        final.md
      02-vendor-fit/
        final.md
      03-service-approach/
        data-migration/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
        data-submission-reporting/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
        data-warehousing/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
        platform-design/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
        testing-qa/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
        training-onboarding/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
      04-system-requirements/
        data-management-dm-agg/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
        reporting-rp-agg/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
        security-sec-agg/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
        training-onboarding-to-agg/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
        user-interface-ui-agg/
          final.md
          update-notes.md
      05-capabilities-experience/
        final.md
        update-notes.md
      06-cost-value/
        final.md
        update-notes.md
      07-delivery-schedule/
        final.md
        update-notes.md
      08-appendices/
        final.md
        update-notes.md
    source/
      example-rfp-sample.md
      initial-template-rfp-response.md
      INSTRUCTIONS.md
      VIASPORT-PROVIDED-system-requirements-addendum.md
      VIASPORT-PROVIDED-viasport-sin-rfp.md
</directory_structure>

<files>
This section contains the contents of the repository's files.

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/data-migration/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 13:40 PST

- Import tooling only supports form-submission imports today; org/user/document
  migration pipelines are not implemented, and file fields are explicitly
  blocked during imports. Evidence: `src/db/schema/forms.schema.ts`,
  `src/features/imports/imports.utils.ts`,
  `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`,
  `src/lib/imports/batch-runner.ts`.
- Batch imports write error CSVs to the artifacts S3 bucket
  (`imports/<jobId>/errors.csv`), while interactive imports store row-level
  errors in `import_job_errors`; there is no dedicated "suggested resolution"
  field beyond the error message. Evidence: `src/lib/imports/batch-runner.ts`,
  `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`,
  `src/db/schema/imports.schema.ts`.
- Rollback is job-wide only: it deletes all form submissions for the import job,
  sanitizes error raw values, and is time-bounded (default 7 days) with a
  `canRollback` flag; partial rollbacks by record type are not implemented.
  Evidence: `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`,
  `src/db/schema/imports.schema.ts`.
- Batch execution uses the ECS task when `SinImportBatchTask` is available,
  otherwise it runs in-process; the task definition is 2 vCPU/4 GB/50 GB and
  uses the import-batch worker entrypoint. Evidence: `sst.config.ts`,
  `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`,
  `src/workers/import-batch.ts`, `docker/import-batch.Dockerfile`.
- Mapping templates currently store header-to-field mappings only; transformation
  rules (enum remaps, phone/postal normalization) are not modeled beyond basic
  type parsing in the import utilities. Evidence:
  `src/db/schema/imports.schema.ts`, `src/features/imports/imports.utils.ts`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/data-submission-reporting/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 13:44 PST
- The "Data Stewards" role described in the portal UX does not exist in code; org roles are owner/admin/reporter/viewer/member, and data quality tooling is global-admin only. The SIN portal summary cards are tailored to org role (due soon, forms, imports, join requests) rather than a dedicated data-steward dashboard. Evidence: `src/lib/auth/guards/org-guard.ts`, `src/features/data-quality/data-quality.queries.ts`, `src/routes/dashboard/sin/index.tsx`.
- The command palette is feature-flagged and its search results are limited to specific entity types, not "any page, form, or record." Evidence: `src/features/search/components/global-search-command-palette.tsx`, `src/features/search/search.schemas.ts`, `src/features/search/search.queries.ts`, `src/tenant/feature-gates.ts`.
- Form file uploads currently support a single file per field with server-side validation of type/size and client-side size checks. Multiple files are rejected, and file replacement/deletion flows are guarded by legal-hold checks. If multi-file uploads are required, the section should call this out as a current limitation. Evidence: `src/components/form-fields/ValidatedFileUpload.tsx`, `src/features/forms/forms.utils.ts`, `src/features/forms/forms.mutations.ts`.
- Form settings include "allow draft," "require approval" (auto-routes submissions to under_review), and "notify on submit" user lists, which are not mentioned in the service-approach narrative. Evidence: `src/features/forms/forms.schemas.ts`, `src/features/forms/components/form-builder-shell.tsx`, `src/features/forms/forms.mutations.ts`.
- Reporting reminders are scheduled per reporting task using `days_before` offsets (default 14/7/3/1), with a cron handler that processes scheduled notifications. Overdue counts in the portal are computed from due dates, not from an automated status update job. Evidence: `src/features/reporting/reporting.mutations.ts`, `src/lib/notifications/scheduler.ts`, `src/cron/process-notifications.ts`, `src/routes/dashboard/sin/index.tsx`.
- Analytics exports differ by module: the BI pivot/SQL exports support CSV/XLSX/JSON with step-up auth, while the report builder only supports CSV/XLSX. The section should clarify where JSON export applies. Evidence: `src/features/bi/bi.schemas.ts`, `src/features/bi/bi.mutations.ts`, `src/features/reports/reports.schemas.ts`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/data-warehousing/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 21:40 UTC

- Sub-processor list should acknowledge optional Google OAuth and Square payments (if enabled) because the residency statement enumerates them and env config includes those integrations; "no additional sub-processors" is too absolute. Evidence: `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/data-residency.md`, `src/lib/env.server.ts`.
- Encryption at rest wording should clarify the S3 artifacts bucket currently uses SSE-S3 in sin-dev and KMS is optional via `SIN_ARTIFACTS_KMS_KEY_ID`; "customer-managed keys" for S3/backups is not enforced in infra config. Evidence: `docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/evidence/ENCRYPTION-STATUS-sin-dev-20251231.md`, `sst.config.ts`, `src/lib/env.server.ts`, `src/features/privacy/privacy.mutations.ts`, `src/lib/privacy/retention.ts`.
- Glacier Deep Archive vs Glacier: lifecycle config transitions artifacts bucket objects to GLACIER after 90 days, while the audit archive job writes audit batches with `StorageClass=DEEP_ARCHIVE`; clarify the mixed behavior and stage-specific evidence. Evidence: `sst.config.ts`, `src/lib/privacy/retention.ts`, `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/audit-retention-policy.md`.
- DR evidence: sin-dev drill shows RPO not met due daily snapshots and RTO about 5 minutes, while backup/restore test shows about 25 minutes; mark RPO/RTO "tested" as dev-only evidence and keep production targets as planned. Evidence: `docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/evidence/DR-DRILL-sin-dev-20251230.md`, `docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/backup-restore-test-results.md`, `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/backup-dr-plan.md`, `sst.config.ts`.
- Tenancy scoping for analytics is enforced via curated views and SQL workbench session settings, not blanket DB-level RLS across all tables; tighten wording from "every database query is scoped" to "analytics queries are scoped via views + session context." Evidence: `src/features/bi/docs/sql-workbench-dba-setup.sql`, `src/features/bi/bi.sql-executor.ts`, `src/features/bi/governance/org-scoping.ts`.
- Data residency evidence could be cited explicitly from infra and runtime defaults (AWS region pinned to ca-central-1, S3 client default region) to support the residency claim. Evidence: `sst.config.ts`, `src/lib/storage/artifacts.ts`, `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/data-residency.md`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/platform-design/update-notes.md">
# Platform Design Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 13:40 PST
- The AWS services list omits several deployed components (VPC with NAT/bastion,
  RDS Proxy, ECS/Fargate import worker, SQS DLQ, CloudWatch alarms/dashboard).
  Consider adding these to reflect the actual infra footprint. Evidence:
  `sst.config.ts`, `src/workers/import-batch.ts`, `docker/import-batch.Dockerfile`.
- S3 storage is a single `SinArtifacts` bucket with Object Lock + lifecycle to
  Glacier, used for forms uploads, templates, imports, DSAR exports, and audit
  archives. The current wording only mentions documents/imports/audit archives.
  Consider updating the storage description to match the real prefixes.
  Evidence: `sst.config.ts`, `src/features/forms/forms.mutations.ts`,
  `src/features/templates/templates.mutations.ts`,
  `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`,
  `src/features/privacy/privacy.mutations.ts`, `src/lib/privacy/retention.ts`.
- KMS usage is explicit for DSAR exports and audit archives (SSE-KMS), but
  regular uploads do not set SSE-KMS in code and rely on bucket defaults. The
  KMS service bullet should reflect this scoped usage. Evidence:
  `src/features/privacy/privacy.mutations.ts`, `src/lib/privacy/retention.ts`,
  `src/features/forms/forms.mutations.ts`, `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`,
  `src/features/templates/templates.mutations.ts`, `src/lib/env.server.ts`.
- CloudTrail/GuardDuty/Secrets Manager with rotation are listed but not defined
  in SST config; secrets are declared via `sst.Secret` without rotation config.
  If these are account-level controls, call that out explicitly or add infra
  setup. Evidence: `sst.config.ts`.
- The workflow section claims automatic deploys to sin-dev and E2E gating.
  Actual CI runs lint/type/test/build only, and pre-commit runs lint-staged,
  type checks, and unit tests. No deploy step or E2E gate is wired in. Update
  the workflow text or add pipeline steps. Evidence: `.github/workflows/ci.yml`,
  `.husky/pre-commit`, `package.json`.
- The deployment step says `sst deploy` updates database schema; migrations are
  separate commands (`pnpm db:migrate` or `pnpm db push`). Either update the
  deployment description or add a deploy hook. Evidence: `package.json`,
  `scripts/reset-db.sh`, `.github/workflows/ci.yml`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/testing-qa/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 21:44 UTC
- The testing layer table currently implies Playwright E2E and performance checks run on every commit. CI only runs lint/type/coverage, and pre-commit runs unit tests; E2E/perf are manual and documented as pre-commit or pre-release steps. Update the frequency text accordingly. Evidence: `.github/workflows/ci.yml`, `.husky/pre-commit`, `docs/E2E-BEST-PRACTICES.md`, `package.json`, `performance/README.md`, `playwright.config.ts`.
- Load-test and Lighthouse results in the QA section list zero server errors and "date TBD"; the latest report shows 9.4% errors at 25 VUs (0% at 10 VUs) and FCP at 2135ms (warn). Update the metrics table to match the actual run and include the 2025-12-31 test date. Evidence: `performance/PERFORMANCE-REPORT.md`, `performance/load-tests/api-load.js`.
- Property-based testing is not "custom-only" anymore; it uses `fast-check` and also covers step-up auth and BI aggregation invariants in addition to access control and audit integrity. Expand the scope note and reference `fast-check` explicitly. Evidence: `package.json`, `src/lib/auth/guards/__tests__/step-up.pbt.test.ts`, `src/features/bi/engine/__tests__/aggregations.property.test.ts`, `src/features/roles/__tests__/permission.service.pbt.test.ts`, `src/features/organizations/__tests__/organizations.access.pbt.test.ts`, `src/lib/audit/__tests__/audit-hash-chain.pbt.test.ts`.
- Security testing lists "concurrent session limits," but the auth config only enforces session expiry and step-up checks; no concurrency cap is configured. Clarify this row to avoid overstating. Evidence: `src/lib/auth/server-helpers.ts`, `src/lib/auth/middleware/auth-guard.ts`, `src/lib/auth/guards/step-up.ts`.
- "Integration tests for database operations/API endpoints" are mostly service-level tests with mocked DB and server-function wiring rather than live DB integration. Tighten the wording so it doesn't imply full database integration coverage. Evidence: `src/tests/setup.ts`, `src/features/reports/__tests__/reports.integration.test.ts`, `src/features/reporting/__tests__/reporting.integration.test.ts`, `src/features/privacy/__tests__/privacy.integration.test.ts`.
- E2E coverage in the QA section calls out "data submission and reporting" as critical flows; the current suite exercises auth, MFA step-up, report export, file validation, and import preview, but not full submission/reporting flows with seeded data. Update the coverage list to reflect the actual E2E scenarios and dependencies. Evidence: `e2e/tests/unauthenticated/auth-flow.unauth.spec.ts`, `e2e/tests/authenticated/mfa-step-up.auth.spec.ts`, `e2e/tests/authenticated/report-export.auth.spec.ts`, `e2e/tests/authenticated/file-upload-validation.auth.spec.ts`, `e2e/tests/authenticated/sin-admin-imports-preview.auth.spec.ts`, `docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/requirements-verification-report-2025-12-28.md`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/training-onboarding/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 13:40 PST
- Guided walkthroughs exist with progress tracking, but only two tutorials are defined (portal onboarding + data upload), and there is no auto-run for first-time users or restart option. Evidence: `src/features/tutorials/tutorials.config.ts`, `src/features/tutorials/components/tutorial-panel.tsx`, `src/features/tutorials/components/guided-tour.tsx`.
- The onboarding tour described as a first-time experience is manual via the TutorialPanel; no automatic trigger on login/onboarding. Evidence: `src/routes/dashboard/sin/index.tsx`, `src/features/tutorials/components/tutorial-panel.tsx`.
- Help center content is static and not role-filtered; search only filters in-memory guides/FAQs. Evidence: `src/features/help/help-content.ts`, `src/features/help/components/help-center.tsx`.
- Templates hub supports filtering, download, and admin upload/archival, but there is no preview, sample data, or versioned template history in the UI. Evidence: `src/features/templates/components/template-hub.tsx`, `src/features/templates/components/template-admin-panel.tsx`.
- Contextual template access exists on the main Forms/Reporting/Imports pages, but individual form detail pages do not surface template links; "directly from each data entry item" is not met. Evidence: `src/routes/dashboard/sin/forms.tsx`, `src/routes/dashboard/sin/reporting.tsx`, `src/routes/dashboard/sin/imports.tsx`, `src/routes/dashboard/sin/forms/$formId.tsx`.
- Support requests capture subject/message/category and track status, but there is no priority or attachment support and no SLA/escalation logic in code; responses are stored and shown in-app only. Evidence: `src/features/support/components/support-requests-panel.tsx`, `src/db/schema/support.schema.ts`, `src/features/support/support.mutations.ts`, `src/features/support/components/support-admin-panel.tsx`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/04-system-requirements/data-management-dm-agg/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes - Data Management (DM-AGG)

## 2026-01-04 13:45 PST
- DM-AGG-001: Submission history is visible, but there is no restore/revert action or
  changed-by display in the UI; history is view-only today. Evidence:
  `src/features/forms/components/form-builder-shell.tsx`,
  `src/features/forms/forms.mutations.ts`.
- DM-AGG-001/006: Import wizard blocks file-field mappings, so historical file
  attachments cannot be migrated yet. Evidence:
  `src/features/imports/components/import-wizard-shell.tsx`,
  `src/features/imports/imports.utils.ts`,
  `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`,
  `src/lib/imports/batch-runner.ts`.
- DM-AGG-002: Import parsing normalizes numbers/booleans and trims strings, but does not
  standardize phone/postal formats or parse dates beyond raw strings. Evidence:
  `src/features/imports/imports.utils.ts`.
- DM-AGG-002: Transformation logging is limited to import job audit entries; there is no
  row-level transformation log or before/after capture for imports. Evidence:
  `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`,
  `src/lib/imports/batch-runner.ts`,
  `src/lib/audit/index.ts`.
- DM-AGG-003: Data catalog indexing covers forms, import templates, saved reports, and
  templates; it does not catalog submissions. Evidence:
  `src/features/data-catalog/data-catalog.service.ts`,
  `src/features/data-catalog/data-catalog.queries.ts`.
- DM-AGG-003: SQL Workbench is gated and disabled by default pending prerequisite
  sign-off. Evidence: `src/features/bi/docs/CHECKLIST-sql-workbench-gate.md`.
- DM-AGG-004: Data quality checks run on schedule and can be triggered manually, but no
  automated alerting/notification thresholds are implemented. Evidence:
  `src/cron/data-quality-monitor.ts`,
  `src/features/data-quality/data-quality.monitor.ts`,
  `src/features/data-quality/components/data-quality-dashboard.tsx`.
- DM-AGG-005: Retention enforcement cron exists and archives audit logs to Deep Archive
  based on policies, while bucket lifecycle rules target Glacier and the retention
  policy doc still marks Object Lock/Glacier automation as pending. Evidence:
  `src/cron/enforce-retention.ts`,
  `src/lib/privacy/retention.ts`,
  `sst.config.ts`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/audit-retention-policy.md`.
- DM-AGG-005: DR restore evidence is from sin-dev only; production drill evidence and
  quarterly cadence are not documented yet. Evidence:
  `docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/backup-restore-test-results.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/backup-dr-plan.md`.
- DM-AGG-006: Batch import worker is defined in infrastructure and code, but deployment
  verification remains marked pending in docs. Evidence:
  `sst.config.ts`,
  `src/workers/import-batch.ts`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/import-batch-worker.md`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/04-system-requirements/reporting-rp-agg/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes - Reporting (RP-AGG)

## 2026-01-04 13:46 PST
- RP-AGG-002: Reporting metadata fields (agreement/NCCP/fiscal/contact) are implemented and editable in the reporting portal, so the status can move from Partial to Comply; evidence: `src/features/reporting/reporting.schemas.ts`, `src/features/reporting/reporting.mutations.ts`, `src/routes/dashboard/sin/reporting.tsx`, `src/db/schema/organizations.schema.ts`.
- RP-AGG-002: Delegated access rights are implemented via delegated access records, org admin UI, and access resolution, so cite them explicitly in the response; evidence: `src/db/schema/organizations.schema.ts`, `src/features/organizations/organizations.mutations.ts`, `src/features/organizations/organizations.queries.ts`, `src/features/organizations/components/organization-admin-panel.tsx`, `src/features/organizations/organizations.access.ts`.
- RP-AGG-001: Server-side validation enforces required fields and file constraints but does not validate email/phone/date formats unless custom validation rules are configured; clarify this scope vs. "valid contact info" claims; evidence: `src/features/forms/forms.schemas.ts`, `src/features/forms/forms.utils.ts`, `src/features/forms/forms.mutations.ts`, `src/components/form-fields/ValidatedDatePicker.tsx`, `src/components/form-fields/ValidatedPhoneInput.tsx`.
- RP-AGG-003: Reminder cadence defaults to 14/7/3/1 days and is configurable per task via reminderConfig, with scheduled notifications processed by cron; mention the extra 14-day default and configurability; evidence: `src/features/reporting/reporting.mutations.ts`, `src/lib/notifications/scheduler.ts`, `src/cron/process-notifications.ts`, `src/db/schema/notifications.schema.ts`.
- RP-AGG-005: JSON export is available in the BI pivot export flow, but the report builder exports only CSV/XLSX; update language to reflect both paths; evidence: `src/features/bi/bi.mutations.ts`, `src/features/bi/bi.schemas.ts`, `src/features/bi/components/pivot-builder/PivotBuilder.tsx`, `src/features/reports/reports.schemas.ts`, `src/features/reports/components/report-builder-shell.tsx`.
- RP-AGG-004: File handling is limited to single-file uploads (arrays rejected and maxFiles forced to 1), so call out the single-file assumption; evidence: `src/features/forms/forms.utils.ts`, `src/features/forms/forms.mutations.ts`, `src/features/forms/components/form-builder-shell.tsx`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/04-system-requirements/security-sec-agg/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 13:46 PST
- SEC-AGG-001: Password complexity is only enforced in change/reset flows; signup
  validation only checks minimum length and the reset flow relies on client-side
  checks. Consider updating the claim or enforcing policy server-side. Evidence:
  `src/features/auth/auth.schemas.ts`, `src/features/settings/settings.schemas.ts`,
  `src/features/auth/components/reset-password.tsx`,
  `src/lib/security/password-config.ts`.
- SEC-AGG-001/002: Account lockouts are applied after failed auth events, but
  sign-in does not block locked users until after login (client-side check) and
  server functions enforce lockout during auth middleware. This is weaker than a
  pre-auth lockout gate. Evidence: `src/lib/security/detection.ts`,
  `src/features/auth/components/login.tsx`,
  `src/lib/auth/middleware/auth-guard.ts`.
- SEC-AGG-002: Security alerts are only emitted for lockouts; login anomalies and
  account flags are recorded but do not notify admins. Evidence:
  `src/lib/security/lockout.ts`, `src/lib/security/detection.ts`.
- SEC-AGG-002: GuardDuty is referenced in the response but is not provisioned in
  infrastructure code (only CloudWatch alarms are configured). Evidence:
  `sst.config.ts`.
- SEC-AGG-004: Audit log filtering does not support record/target ID filters;
  current filters are actor user ID, target org ID, category, and date. Evidence:
  `src/features/audit/audit.schemas.ts`,
  `src/features/audit/components/audit-log-table.tsx`.
- SEC-AGG-004: Audit immutability is application-level (hash chain + no purge in
  retention) but not enforced by database constraints or WORM storage. Consider
  wording this as tamper-evident rather than immutable. Evidence:
  `src/lib/audit/index.ts`, `src/lib/privacy/retention.ts`,
  `src/db/schema/audit.schema.ts`.
- SEC-AGG-003: Audit archiving timing differs between seed scripts (90 days vs
  365 days), and retention enforcement only uses archiveAfterDays/purgeAfterDays;
  align documented retention with seeded policies. Evidence:
  `scripts/seed-retention-policies.ts`, `scripts/seed-sin-data.ts`,
  `src/lib/privacy/retention.ts`.
- SEC-AGG-003: SSE-KMS is explicitly set for DSAR exports and audit archives, but
  standard uploads/imports do not set SSE-KMS, relying on bucket defaults. If the
  requirement is KMS everywhere, update infra or wording. Evidence:
  `src/features/privacy/privacy.mutations.ts`, `src/lib/privacy/retention.ts`,
  `src/features/forms/forms.mutations.ts`, `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`,
  `sst.config.ts`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/04-system-requirements/training-onboarding-to-agg/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 13:43 PST

### TO-AGG-001 Template Support & Integration
- The templates hub supports context filtering and downloads, but there is no in-app preview; templates are downloaded via signed URLs only. Evidence: `src/features/templates/components/template-hub.tsx`, `src/features/templates/templates.mutations.ts`.
- Contextual access is provided via "View templates" buttons on the forms/imports/reporting landing pages, not inside individual submissions or import records. Evidence: `src/routes/dashboard/sin/forms.tsx`, `src/routes/dashboard/sin/imports.tsx`, `src/routes/dashboard/sin/reporting.tsx`.
- Template uploads are supported in the admin console and require admin permissions for global or org-scoped templates. Evidence: `src/features/templates/components/template-admin-panel.tsx`, `src/features/templates/templates.mutations.ts`.

### TO-AGG-002 Guided Learning & Walkthroughs
- Guided walkthroughs are user-initiated from the Tutorial panel; there is no automatic first-login tour trigger. Evidence: `src/features/tutorials/components/tutorial-panel.tsx`, `src/features/tutorials/components/guided-tour.tsx`, `src/routes/dashboard/sin/index.tsx`.
- Tutorial progress is stored per user, but the onboarding route only covers privacy and profile completion and does not launch tutorials. Evidence: `src/db/schema/tutorials.schema.ts`, `src/routes/onboarding/index.tsx`.
- The data upload walkthrough appears on the Imports page and relies on `data-tour` targets; there are no help-icon triggers elsewhere. Evidence: `src/routes/dashboard/sin/imports.tsx`, `src/features/tutorials/tutorials.config.ts`.

### TO-AGG-003 Reference Materials & Support
- The Help Center is a static guide/FAQ list with client-side text filtering; no role-based filtering or ranked/full-text search is implemented. Evidence: `src/features/help/components/help-center.tsx`, `src/features/help/help-content.ts`.
- Support requests include status tracking and admin responses in-app, but there is no notification/email dispatch on response updates. Evidence: `src/features/support/components/support-requests-panel.tsx`, `src/features/support/components/support-admin-panel.tsx`, `src/features/support/support.mutations.ts`.
- Internal training materials for support staff exist in repo docs but are not surfaced in the Help Center UI. Evidence: `src/features/bi/docs/TRAINING-bi-support-coordinator.md`, `src/features/bi/docs/PLAYBOOK-bi-support.md`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/04-system-requirements/user-interface-ui-agg/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes - User Interface (UI-AGG)

## 2026-01-04 13:49 PST
- UI-AGG-001: Organization registration is not self-serve; users are invited or submit join requests, while org creation/invites live in admin-only tooling; evidence: `src/routes/dashboard/select-org.tsx`, `src/features/organizations/join-requests/components/join-request-browser.tsx`, `src/features/organizations/components/organization-admin-panel.tsx`, `src/routes/dashboard/admin/sin/organizations.tsx`.
- UI-AGG-002: Role-aware dashboards are implemented for the SIN portal, but the default dashboard and admin home are static (no role-specific widgets), so coverage is partial outside SIN; evidence: `src/routes/dashboard/sin/index.tsx`, `src/routes/dashboard/index.tsx`, `src/routes/dashboard/admin/index.tsx`.
- UI-AGG-003: The UI supports light/dark themes via CSS variables, but there is no explicit color-contrast tool, and Lighthouse report artifacts are not present in-repo (config only); evidence: `src/components/ThemeToggle.tsx`, `src/shared/hooks/useTheme.ts`, `src/styles.css`, `performance/lighthouse.config.cjs`.
- UI-AGG-004: Notification preferences are per-user categories/frequency (not role-based), templates are gated to SIN admin, and reporting reminders default to 14/7/3/1 days unless overridden; evidence: `src/features/notifications/components/notification-preferences-card.tsx`, `src/features/notifications/notifications.schemas.ts`, `src/features/notifications/notifications.queries.ts`, `src/features/notifications/components/notification-template-panel.tsx`, `src/features/reporting/reporting.mutations.ts`.
- UI-AGG-006: Support requests have status tracking and admin response UI, but responses do not trigger email or in-app notifications; evidence: `src/features/support/support.mutations.ts`, `src/features/support/components/support-admin-panel.tsx`, `src/features/support/components/support-requests-panel.tsx`.
- UI-AGG-007: Branding is configured via tenant code and CSS variables rather than admin settings; evidence: `src/tenant/tenants/viasport.ts`, `src/tenant/tenants/qc.ts`, `src/styles.css`, `src/components/ui/logo.tsx`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/05-capabilities-experience/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 13:44 -0800
- Codebase size is ~92k TS/TSX lines in `src/`; update the "20,000+ lines" metric to reflect current scale (`src/`).
- Automation infra wording: notifications queue is standard SQS (FIFO/dedup only if `.fifo`), SES sending has no bounce-handling pipeline, and digest emails are implemented (`sst.config.ts`, `src/lib/notifications/queue.ts`, `src/lib/notifications/send.ts`, `src/lib/notifications/digest.ts`, `src/cron/process-notifications.ts`).
- Import tooling supports CSV/Excel mapping/preview/rollback with batch checkpointing, but file field imports are explicitly blocked; call out the limitation (`src/features/imports/components/import-wizard-shell.tsx`, `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`, `src/lib/imports/batch-runner.ts`).
- Data quality automation stores daily summaries and powers the dashboard, but no alert notifications are emitted yet; describe it as monitoring/reporting unless alerts are added (`src/cron/data-quality-monitor.ts`, `src/features/data-quality/data-quality.monitor.ts`, `src/features/data-quality/components/data-quality-dashboard.tsx`).
- Load test evidence shows 0 server (5xx) errors but ~6.7% 429 rate-limit responses; clarify "zero errors" as "zero 5xx" and mention rate limiting (`performance/reports/20260102-sin-perf-summary.md`).
- Consider highlighting governance capability: exports require step-up auth and enforce PII masking/field ACLs (`src/features/bi/bi.mutations.ts`, `src/features/bi/governance/field-acl.ts`, `src/features/reports/reports.mutations.ts`).
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/06-cost-value/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 13:41 PST
- Load-test headroom: The 20.1M-row sin-perf run shows 6.73% 429 rate limiting and auth p95 ~250ms, so the “no price adjustments for data volume growth/headroom” claim should note rate-limit tuning and provisioned concurrency for higher concurrency loads. Evidence: `performance/reports/20260102-sin-perf-summary.md`, `performance/load-tests/api-load.js`, `sst.config.ts`.
- DR drill cadence: The cost section promises quarterly DR drills, but current evidence is sin-dev-only restore drills/tests; wording should clarify production cadence vs dev evidence. Evidence: `docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/evidence/DR-DRILL-sin-dev-20251230.md`, `docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/backup-restore-test-results.md`, `sst.config.ts`.
- Operations portal add-on scope: Events/teams/membership are implemented for QC but feature-gated off for viaSport, so the add-on should call out tenant enablement and any payments/registration dependencies. Evidence: `src/tenant/tenants/qc.ts`, `src/tenant/tenants/viasport.ts`, `src/features/events/events.mutations.ts`, `src/features/teams/teams.mutations.ts`.
- Prototype value-add size: “20,000+ lines” understates current scope (~92k TS/TSX lines in `src/`); update the figure or remove the hard number while keeping the tested-code claim. Evidence: `src/`, `vitest.config.ts`, `src/features/bi/__tests__/bi.integration.test.ts`.
- Hosting/infra cost drivers: Add or clarify ongoing costs for SQS-backed notification processing and ECS Fargate import batch jobs beyond core Lambda/RDS spend. Evidence: `sst.config.ts`, `src/cron/notification-worker.ts`, `src/workers/import-batch.ts`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/07-delivery-schedule/update-notes.md">
# Delivery Schedule Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 13:43 PST

- Migration tooling is not fully complete; file field imports are blocked and the
  batch worker entrypoint is stubbed, so the Development & Migration phase
  should include the remaining import worker work or an explicit scope decision.
  Evidence: `docs/sin-rfp/response/07-delivery-schedule/final.md`,
  `src/features/imports/components/import-wizard-shell.tsx`,
  `src/features/imports/imports.mutations.ts`, `src/lib/imports/worker.ts`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/requirements/tickets/SIN-IMPLEMENTATION-BACKLOG-V2.md`.
- Retention automation and audit archive immutability show pending delivery
  with a 2026-02 target; the schedule should include this before production
  cutover or call it out as a dependency. Evidence:
  `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/audit-retention-policy.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/gap-closure-plan.md`, `sst.config.ts`,
  `src/cron/enforce-retention.ts`.
- UAT/QA effort should explicitly budget for verification gaps (accessibility
  audit, notification delivery, analytics export validation) and increased
  automated coverage (E2E tests listed at ~30%). Evidence:
  `docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/gap-closure-plan.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/requirements/tickets/SIN-IMPLEMENTATION-BACKLOG-V2.md`.
- Training materials are still stub content in code; the schedule should include
  dedicated time to author viaSport-specific guides, FAQs, walkthrough steps,
  and template seeding. Evidence: `src/features/help/help-content.ts`,
  `src/features/tutorials/tutorials.config.ts`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/gap-closure-plan.md`.
- Timeline framing should be reconciled with the 17-24 week phased plan and
  Phase 3's remaining infra work, or explicitly justify the 18-week compression.
  Evidence: `docs/sin-rfp/response/07-delivery-schedule/final.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/phased-delivery-plan.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/requirements/tickets/SIN-IMPLEMENTATION-BACKLOG-V2.md`.
- If the delivery schedule changes, update timeline references in other
  response sections for consistency. Evidence:
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/01-executive-summary/final.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/02-vendor-fit/final.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/06-cost-value/final.md`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/08-appendices/update-notes.md">
# Update Notes

## 2026-01-04 13:44 PST

- Appendix scope mismatch: current Appendix A-H differs from the internal A-I
  checklist (requirements matrix, architecture diagrams, migration plan, security
  docs, training materials, case studies, team bios, pricing worksheets, optional
  add-ons). Decide whether to re-number or add missing appendices, and update
  cross-references like Appendix A in the executive summary. Evidence:
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/08-appendices/notes.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/08-appendices/concerns.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/08-appendices/final.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/01-executive-summary/final.md`.
- Appendix A demo access: add `admin@example.com` platform admin and clarify MFA
  details (TOTP secret + backup codes). The appendix says credentials are
  placeholders, but the seed script defines concrete accounts and MFA enrollment.
  Evidence: `scripts/seed-sin-data.ts`, `CLAUDE.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/08-appendices/austin-notes.md`.
- Appendix A demo environment: decide whether to point to `sin-perf` (CloudFront
  URLs documented in performance reports) or create the planned `sin-uat`
  environment, then update the demo URL accordingly. Evidence:
  `performance/reports/20260102-sin-perf-summary.md`,
  `performance/PERFORMANCE-REPORT.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/08-appendices/austin-notes.md`.
- Appendix B architecture: add infra components that are in IaC but not called
  out (VPC, RDS Proxy, S3 artifacts bucket with Object Lock + Glacier lifecycle,
  SQS notifications queue + DLQ, EventBridge cron jobs, ECS Fargate import-batch
  task, CloudWatch alarms + SNS). Evidence: `sst.config.ts`,
  `src/workers/import-batch.ts`, `src/cron/process-notifications.ts`,
  `src/cron/enforce-retention.ts`, `src/cron/data-quality-monitor.ts`.
- Appendix B security tooling: GuardDuty/CloudTrail are referenced in security
  docs, but not provisioned in IaC; confirm account-level setup or mark as
  planned. Evidence: `sst.config.ts`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/security-controls.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/data-residency.md`.
- Appendix C load tests: replace "date TBD" with actual run dates and reconcile
  metrics between the 2025-12-31 report (25 VUs, p95 269ms, 9.4% error rate) and
  the 2026-01-02 summary (15 VUs, p95 250ms, 6.73% 429 rate limiting). Also note
  rate-limiter errors instead of implying zero errors. Evidence:
  `performance/PERFORMANCE-REPORT.md`,
  `performance/reports/20260102-sin-perf-summary.md`.
- Appendix C metrics are repeated elsewhere; once Appendix C is finalized, sync
  the numbers and wording in other sections. Evidence:
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/01-executive-summary/final.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/02-vendor-fit/final.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/testing-qa/final.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/05-capabilities-experience/final.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/06-cost-value/final.md`.
- Appendix D data residency/compliance: phase-0 docs mark some controls as
  partial (SES-only enforcement, DPA verification, DR evidence), so update
  Appendix D wording to indicate targets vs implemented controls. Evidence:
  `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/data-residency.md`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/security-controls.md`.
- Appendix D audit retention: code now archives audit logs to S3 Deep Archive
  and tracks archive rows, while the audit-retention policy doc still says
  archival is pending. Align Appendix D and/or update the policy status.
  Evidence: `src/lib/privacy/retention.ts`, `src/db/schema/audit.schema.ts`,
  `sst.config.ts`, `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/audit-retention-policy.md`.
- Appendix D field-level permissions: BI field ACL + step-up export enforcement
  exist, but the data classification guide still marks field-level PII
  enforcement as pending. Clarify scope to analytics exports or update the
  guide. Evidence: `src/features/bi/governance/field-acl.ts`,
  `src/features/bi/bi.mutations.ts`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/phase-0/data-classification-guide.md`.
- Appendix D security controls: consider adding account lockout and anomaly
  detection (already implemented) to the security summary. Evidence:
  `src/lib/security/detection.ts`, `src/lib/security/lockout.ts`,
  `src/lib/security/config.ts`.
- Appendix E personas: org role enum includes `member` and there is no explicit
  `auditor` role; clarify mapping for the Auditor persona and whether "member"
  should be listed. Evidence: `src/db/schema/organizations.schema.ts`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/requirements/sin-dual-portal-considerations.md`.
- Appendix artifacts: the appendices evidence folder is still empty; add
  screenshots/diagrams/matrix exports before final packaging. Evidence:
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/08-appendices/evidence/`,
  `docs/sin-rfp/response/08-appendices/concerns.md`.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/source/example-rfp-sample.md">
# Example RFP Response - Sample Excerpts

> This is an excerpted sample (~5k tokens) from a real RFP response. Sections are marked with [...] where content has been omitted. All wording is preserved exactly as written.

---

## Table of Contents (Excerpt)

1. INTRODUCTION .... 1
2. EXECUTIVE SUMMARY .... 2
3. INTENTIONALLY BLANK .... 5
4. INTENTIONALLY BLANK .... 5
5. Vendor Response Instructions .... 6
5.1 Intentionally Blank .... 6
5.2 Intentionally Blank .... 6
5.3 Intentionally Blank .... 6
5.4 VENDOR CAPABILITIES .... 7
5.4.1 Corporate Profile .... 7
5.4.2 Project Team .... 9
5.4.3 References .... 10
5.4.4 Partnering .... 11
5.4.5 Financial Stability .... 12
5.5 INSURANCE REQUIREMENTS .... 13
5.6 TERMS AND CONDITIONS .... 13
6. MIDRANGE STORAGE SUBSYSTEM REQUIREMENTS .... 15
6.1 CRITICAL REQUIREMENTS .... 15
6.2 HIGHLY DESIRABLE REQUIREMENTS .... 25
6.3 DESIRABLE REQUIREMENTS .... 31
6.4 INFORMATIONAL REQUESTS .... 37
7. PRICING RESPONSE: MIDRANGE STORAGE SUBSYSTEM .... 48

[...]

---

## INTRODUCTION

Interdynamix Systems (IDX) and Hitachi Data Systems (HDS) welcome the opportunity to respond to the Workers' Compensation Board – Alberta (WCB) Request for Proposal (RFP) for a Storage Subsystem replacement.
The following response is respectfully submitted. In an effort to minimize the effort required to evaluate this response, the format follows the WCB's requested response format. To better facilitate the evaluation process, we would like to also point out the following:
To maintain the WCB's section numbering schema, placeholders for sections not requested in the response are identified with 'INTENTIONALLY BLANK'. The only exceptions to this are 'Section 1 – Introduction' and 'Section 2 – Executive Summary'.
WCB RFP original content or Addendum/Clarification content is included in this response, in each section, and is distinguishable by being presented in BLUE.

---

## EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Hitachi Data Systems and Interdynamix System are pleased to respond to Worker's Compensation Board Storage Subsystem Replacement RFP #1209BB. Both organizations believe a company's information is a strategic asset. That's why we continue to develop and improve storage solutions with the performance, availability, and scalability you need to maximize ROI and minimize risk. We always consider your perspective and business needs while applying the best hardware, software, and services to satisfy your requirements. Our commitment to being a partner beyond technology sets us apart from other vendors in the industry. It means we're prepared to help you envision your future and create an open and collaborative storage management framework, policy-based automation tools, virtualization capabilities, and the world's finest storage systems.

Difficult economic times require new perspectives and strategies for reducing the cost of storage infrastructure. The past several years of IT procurement have left many IT organizations with underutilized and oversubscribed storage capacity. Now, with a squeeze on capital and credit, many organizations are faced with edicts to do more with less and to make tough decisions on where to invest available funds. In particular, there are increased demands to do more with the existing, sunk infrastructure costs in the IT department. We are presenting WCB with a solution to meet the current requirements; however we also have other proven solutions which also focus on reducing the TCA (Total Cost of Acquisition) and TCO (Total Cost of Ownership) by leveraging our framework to achieve an economically superior way of deploying and growing our storage.

The key highlights of our response are as follows:

TCO: We believe we will save WCB costs by selecting our solution. As part of this bid, we'd like to talk to WCB about our storage economics, a series of proven methodologies, tools, solutions and planning practices that enable the application of financial and economic principles to storage technologies to help our customers with the TCO of storage, which would allow us to validate our details. Based on our initial assessment, our calculations indicate that we could easily save WCB costs. This is taking into consideration key factors such as Performance, Floor Space Efficiency, Power/Cooling Efficiency, Capacity Improvements, etc.

Price Does Not Equal Cost: The total cost of acquisition (TCA) for storage is roughly only 20% of TCO. Over time, the TCA will become less and less significant. Labor, maintenance, power and cooling currently drive a higher cost (some 3 to 4 times higher) than acquisition alone. The measurable economic impact on TCO with thin provisioned, tiered and virtualized storage architectures can be dramatic. Our solution incorporates all of the items with TCO in mind. (see "Storage Economics Overview" Reference Document)

Initial Investment: HDS executive management and Interdynamix see WCB as a Key Strategic account. We would like to add WCB to our growing list of extremely happy and satisfied customers. We have leveraged funds to deliver a onetime initial purchase discount in the range of over $200,000 off list price. Although we have applied a onetime aggressive discount for this RFP, we would be more than happy to also include extremely aggressive pricing going forward.

Technology: HDS has proven, reliable, and award winning technology with key focus on scalability, migration, and dynamic provisioning. It's not all about purchasing new IT. There are technologies that can help you get maximum value from your previous storage investments. They reduce the need for your future investment to grow at the same rate that your data grows.
We call these economically superior storage architectures, and their key ingredients include:
- Storage virtualization
- Thin provisioning
- Dynamically tiered storage
- Common storage management
- Capacity efficiency
- Efficient migration
- Integrated archive

All technologies that we can deliver will directly affect your TCO!

Our Proposed Solution:
Based on your defined requirements and information we've gathered in conversation from your teams previously we are proud to offer the Hitachi Adaptable Modular Storage 2300 platform. This is a highly available solution that will provide a reliable and cost-effective tier 2 platform for WCB while delivering all the performance and reliability you would expect from a tier 1 solution. We have configured this AMS 2300 to include 50 TB of usable capacity built with 600 GB SAS drives operating at 15,000 RPM in a RAID 6 (6 data + 2 parity drives) for the best in performance and reliability for the workloads you anticipate.

---

## VENDOR CAPABILITIES

### Corporate Profile

Include a brief corporate history and general overview of your organization (please limit this to a maximum of three (3) pages). The WCB is looking for the Vendor to clearly demonstrate that it has the resources and experience necessary to effectively provide the requirements of this RFP. Experience with organizations of high public profile is also of interest. In addition, discuss your company's future direction where it may positively influence and increase service capabilities offered to the WCB. Only those aspects deemed to be of benefit to the WCB may be considered in the evaluation.
The WCB is interested in evaluating information relative to corporate experience in the areas of Midrange Storage Subsystems.

**Hitachi Data Systems**
Hitachi Data Systems is a wholly owned subsidiary of Hitachi Ltd.
Hitachi Ltd. is one of the world's largest integrated electronics companies
Founded in 1910
Manufactures over 20,000 products – from toasters to bullet trains
390,000 employees; over 2000 PhDs
Total FY07 sales of $112.2B
FY07 R&D Investment: $4.3B
Approximately 40% in IT
Approximately $5.6B USD in cash
Hitachi Ltd. provides resources that Hitachi Data Systems leverages – from R&D dollars to engineering and best practice expertise. Hitachi Data Systems was formed in 1989 and has direct and indirect sales in 170 countries. As Hitachi Ltd.'s focal point for storage infrastructure solutions, storage management software, and storage consulting services, Hitachi Data Systems has over 3,800 employees. Our mission is to deliver a services oriented approach to storage built on a market-proven storage platform, which when combined with Hitachi's controller-based storage virtualization technology, offer customers many measurable benefits including storage consolidation, improved utilization of assets, reduced TCO, and a lower environmental footprint.

**Interdynamix Systems**
Interdynamix Systems is western Canada's leading high-end Enterprise Infrastructure and Integration Services firm. Operating as a privately held, self-funded organization, Interdynamix has experienced year over year growth in revenue and profit since its inception in 1995. Headquartered in Edmonton, Alberta, Canada, Interdynamix delivers solutions to large and medium sized customers across western Canada, with a concentrated effort on the Alberta market place.
At the core of our success has been our ability to stay at the leading edge of technology innovation and translate our knowledge of the technology landscape into intellectual value that solves real world business and IT problems. Key to this capability is our highly talented and astute team who are experts in communicating and delivering sophisticated and elegant solutions to our customers.
Interdynamix designs, installs and supports IT infrastructure solutions focused on maximizing operational efficiency and reducing the total cost of ownership for our customers. To accomplish this we target our solutions around five key technology pillars.
Storage Infrastructure
Technology Consolidation & Virtualized IT
Operational Service Continuance
Highly Available Computing
Application Delivery Networking

### Project Team

Please identify core members of your proposed project team(s) for implementation and support including proposed team lead and the key technical resource. Provide the following for each member:
Proposed project position;
Years of related industry experience specific to Midrange Storage Subsystems;
Identify home-base for resource;
Identify the role on the project;
Indicate if the resource will be required to work on-site at the WCB or will be located elsewhere; and
Resume(s).
Note: Unlimited priority access to the key project resources is required during critical project phases.

PROJECT TEAM
Name: John Antonio
Position: Supplier Project Manager & Delivery Oversight
Experience: 25 Years in IT
Home Base: Edmonton, Alberta
Role: Delivery Oversight of project from Interdynamix
Location: Majority of work would be out of the Interdynamix office

Name: Artur Kusiak
Position: Storage Engineer
Experience: 13 Years in IT
Home Base: Edmonton, Alberta
Role: SAN and Open System Implementation
Location: Onsite at WCB 70% of time, 30% at IDX office

[...]

### References

Provide three (3) North American (preferably Canadian) corporate references with whom successful consolidated system implementations as described in this RFP have been completed within the past two years.

**TELUS**
Name: Brian Lakey
Title: Vice President, TELUS Technical Strategy
Phone: 780-493-2537
Email: brian.lakey@telus.com
Address: TELUS Plaza South, 10020 – 100 Street, Edmonton, AB CANADA
Project: Multi-Site Consolidated Enterprise Storage Infrastructure
Description of Work: Interdynamix has worked with TELUS Network Operations to consolidate their mission critical data on to the Hitachi Data storage platform as part of a larger Interdynamix-developed data management and protection strategy. This data is critical to the operation of TELUS' nation-wide IP network. After evaluating competing technologies, Hitachi Data Systems technology was selected as the consolidation platform for its industry-leading performance and reliability. The infrastructure was deployed at multiple sites across Canada (Edmonton, Calgary, Burnaby, Kamloops, and two sites in Toronto).
TELUS has been an Interdynamix Customer for over 14 years.

[...]

---

## MIDRANGE STORAGE SUBSYSTEM REQUIREMENTS

DS4800 Disk Subsystem that serves disk space to our Open Systems environment. The disk capacity currently residing on the IBM DS8300 Disk Subsystem (Tier I) are not in scope for this RFP.
WCB is looking for the best configuration of disk types that may or may not include SATA, Fibre-Channel, SAS, and/or SSD in order to achieve the best possible performance for the data types (as described in Section 3.1.2.2 Tier III Storage) stored on this subsystem.
The WCB requests new hardware of the most current generation generally available.
Vendors are requested to provide a summary overview justifying how their equipment proposal fits within the WCB. Referencing Industry Standards is strongly encouraged.

### CRITICAL REQUIREMENTS

The requirements and specifications listed in this section are considered critical to procuring a Midrange Storage Subsystem replacement solution.
All items included in this section Must be part of the proposed solution.
WCB reserves the right to disqualify a Vendor's proposal if in its sole discretion response item(s) does not provide sufficient information to justify or confirm a listed requirement(s).
Proposals are to include, but not be limited to, the requirements described under this section.

#### Formatted Disk Capacity

Storage sizes are expressed as 1 GB is 1,073,741,824 bytes and 1 TB is 1,099,511,627,776 bytes. Formatted Disk Capacity refers to the disk capacity seen by the operating system on the host(s).
Open Systems Mid Tier storage capacity estimates at WCB have been calculated for a five (5) year period through 2016. Yearly estimates are based on 20% growth on the formatted capacity, and are represented in 'Table 5 Five Year Capacity Projection' shown below.

Table 5 Five Year Capacity Projection – Midrange Storage Subsystem
| Year | Current 2012 | Year 1 2013 | Year 2 2014 | Year 3 2015 | Year 4 2016 |
|------|--------------|-------------|-------------|-------------|-------------|
| Open Systems | 46.7 | 56.0 | 67.2 | 80.7 | 96.8 |
| Capacity Increase | - | 9.3 | 11.2 | 13.5 | 16.1 |

Recommend three (3) options for sufficient disk capacity acquisitions needed to satisfy the growth estimates:
Option 1: The first year of capacity requirements (2012),
Option 2: For years 2012 and 2013 together, and
Option 3: For years 2012, 2013, and 2014.

**Option One Capacity - 2012:**
Disk Type: 600 GB SAS 15k RPM Drives
Number of Disks: 136
Raid Sets: Qty 17 RAID 6 (6 data + 2 parity) Sets
Raw Storage Capacity (TB): 75.94
Usable Storage Capacity (Base 10) TB: 56.96
Usable Storage Capacity (Base 2) TB: 51.8

[...]

#### RAID Arrays

Describe and justify the proposed RAID configuration to ensure against data loss. Explain the performance benefits of the proposed RAID configuration.
We have selected a 600 GB size drive to match capacity with performance characteristics. Naturally better performance could be driven if you were to leverage the Dyanmic Provisioning capability of the AMS, however to our knowledge HDP is not supported if it is virtualized behind IBM's SVC.
The choice of RAID 6 was determined based on reliability aspects relative to RAID levels, RAID 6 providing the greatest protection of data against the unlikely event of a double disk failure while a RAID group is rebuilding.

In the case of multiple drive failures in a RAID set, the following is accurate for all manufacturers and is a consequence of the RAID group used.
R5- 100% data loss.
R6 and R10- 0% data loss.

From a reliability perspective, RAID 6 is obviously preferable over RAID 5

---

### HIGHLY DESIRABLE REQUIREMENTS

The requirements and specifications listed in this section are labeled as highly desirable to procuring a Midrange Storage Subsystem replacement solution. The items listed in this section are not mandatory however they are considered essential in a new solution. Vendors will not be disqualified if all items in this section are not responded to, however items with no response or lack of information will receive a zero (0) score resulting in a lower overall score.

#### Maintenance and Support

Propose maintenance and support agreements that clearly supports our Open Systems environment's availability goals of 24 x 7 (99.99%).
We have included the Standard Hitachi Maintenance program with this proposal.
Hitachi Data Systems' problem resolution system is multi-faceted and involves the following: the Global Call Centers(GCC), Global Support Centers (GSC) and local support technicians (CSS). HiTrack Call-Home is online 7x24 and immediately notifies the GCC and GSC of a hardware problem. The HiTrack RACC service provides for remote access by GSC personnel to query the problem, upload traces from the site, etc. Local CSS is dispatched for onsite support and component replacements as required. The problem resolution process is outlined below as follows:
Respond to requests for service within the required time frame.
Notify the customer, in case of HiTrack call-home, that a component has failed and onsite service is being dispatched.
Assess the situation for Severity (levels one(1) through five (5).
If the failure is due to a simple component that requires replacement, the part is ordered and the customer is notified to open a change request. The part is then replaced as instructed within the designated time frame.
If the failure requires a more in-depth analysis, relevant data is collected and the Global Support Centre (GSC) is consulted until problem is resolved completely.
All customers that select the top tier 7x24 service as proposed in this response receive service response exceeding customer expectations.

The Hitachi Data Systems call-home system is "Hi-Track" (RAID Hi-Track for Enterprise class subsystems). It is internet-based using "https" protocol over port 443 with outbound only transmission. It provides complete 7x24x365 monitoring of the subsystem(s). Its reports consist of a daily health check along with a weekly configuration update report that is transmitted once per week.

[...]

---

### DESIRABLE REQUIREMENTS

The requirements and specifications listed in this section are considered desirable to procuring a Midrange Storage Subsystem replacement solution. The items listed in this section are not mandatory however they are considered preferred in a new solution.

#### Data Migration Process

Describe the process to migrate data from the current storage subsystems to the proposed subsystems. Provide details including schedules on your data migration plans.

Hitachi Data Systems provides world-class professional services through our Global Solution Services (GSS) organization. Data Migration can be provided to WCB on request using a variety of approaches. These consist of engagements where;
We do all the migration activities including project management
We provide just a technical oversight and work with your team
We provide project management.

A mix of these offerings is available and we can find a suitable match for WCB based on your schedules and preference. Migrations can be accomplished via host based or block based and we can bring in a variety of services and technologies under a GSS engagement to move data non-disruptively ensuring the greatest integrity in data is maintained and outages are kept to a minimum.

The difference in the host-based and frame-based versions of this service is primarily the migration techniques to be utilized:
Host-based: Migration techniques can be either host-based copy tools or system-based virtualization. Downtime is minimized with system-based virtualization because the systems remain in operation while the migration is under way.
Frame-based: Migration is based on host-based mirroring or replication by TrueCopy® software. All servers associated with the source storage system share a common outage window for the frame cutover to the target storage system.

[...]

---

## PRICING RESPONSE: MIDRANGE STORAGE SUBSYSTEM

### PRICING REQUIREMENTS

All proposed price descriptions and details associated with the requirements outlined in this RFP are required to be identified within this section. Vendors are encouraged to display their pricing as seen fit and can be displayed as additional material in Appendix F – Other Appendices. For the purpose of price evaluation, proposed details and costs are to be provided as requested in this section.
All prices Must be quoted in Canadian dollars.
The Federal Government has exempted the WCB from Goods and Services Tax (GST) and Harmonized Sales Tax (HST) on the purchase of goods and services. WCB's exemption number is R124072513.
The WCB reserves the right to conduct periodic cost/price audits.
Any costs not identified in Section 7 – Price Response: Midrange Storage Subsystem will be the responsibility of the Vendor, and will not be paid by the WCB.
WCB will not pay for any travel and/or accommodation expenses for the Vendor or Vendor's partners as a result of any part of this RFP or Vendor Presentations.

### Five (5) Year Pricing

Provide a five (5) year pricing proposal for each yearly capacity projections detailed in Table 5 Five Year Capacity Projection – Midrange Storage Subsystem. As deemed appropriate Vendors may propose a customized purchase option. However, for the purpose of price evaluation, Vendor's are requested to show pricing on the sheets provided in Section 7 – Price Response: Midrange Storage Subsystem for all related 'Pricing' items listed in this section.

### Option 1 Pricing Sheet: Midrange Storage Subsystem

Summarize all proposed Midrange Storage Subsystem costs in the table below to provide a total solution purchase cost based on the recommended disk capacity proposed for Option 1.

| Price Requirement | Year 1 2012 | Year 2 2013 | Year 3 2014 | Year 4 2015 | Year 5 2016 |
|-------------------|-------------|-------------|-------------|-------------|-------------|
| 6.1.1 Formatted Disk Capacity | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.1.2 RAID Arrays | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.1.3 Subsystem Cache | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.1.4 Cache Write Protection | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.1.5 Fiber Channel (FC) Connectivity | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.1.6 VMWare Integration | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.1.7 Redundancy | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.2.1 System Availability | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.2.2 Maintenance and Support | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.2.5 Licensing (list all applicable) | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.3.1 Performance Monitoring | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.3.2 Data Migration Process | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.4.3 Initial Setup Options | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 6.4.9 Training | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| 7.3 Warranty | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |
| **Yearly Total Solution Cost** | $ | $ | $ | $ | $ |

**Five (5) year Total Solution Cost: $ _____________________**

[...]

---

## ADDITIONAL FEATURES/VALUE ADDED

Installation Services: Value: $6,000.00
Interdynamix will provide 3 days of installation services to WCB as not cost. This

Trade-In Value for Existing Equipment: Value: $5,000.00
Interdynamix will provide WCB a $5,000 credit on account to be applied to future purchased of services from Interdynamix. This credit will be applied once the equipment discussed in this RFP has been shipped to Interdynamix.

Disposal Services: Value: $3,000.00
Any equipment that is on no value that is being traded in will be disposed of at no cost to WCB.
TOTAL VALUE ADDED = $14,000.00

Further to the solution proposed in this response, Hitachi Data Systems is a world leader in storage virtualization and data management. We would encourage WCB to explore the offerings in this category and consider it as an alternative to not only extending the capability of your existing storage assets, but to further enhance your existing capabilities by consolidating your storage.

---

## Appendix A – Addenda / Clarifications
## Appendix B – Agreement
## Appendix C – Consent Form
## Appendix F – Resumes
## Appendix F – Specification sheets

[End of sample excerpts]
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/source/INSTRUCTIONS.md">
# RFP Response Assembly Instructions

## Context

I am responding to the viaSport SIN RFP and want to assemble the first draft of the response. Explicit placeholders are acceptable at this stage.

## Source Files

- **`final.md`** - Current draft of each section, based on my austin-notes (not included in this bundle)
- **`update-notes.md`** - Agent-generated suggestions for updates based on current state of the codebase; these were created after final.md and may contain improvements or corrections
- **`example-rfp-sample.md`** - Sample excerpts from a real RFP response; use this as a reference for tone and style
- **`initial-template-rfp-response.md`** - Loose template for the response structure; can be modified as needed
- **`VIASPORT-PROVIDED-viasport-sin-rfp.md`** - The original RFP we are responding to
- **`VIASPORT-PROVIDED-system-requirements-addendum.md`** - Additional system requirements from viaSport

## Key Requirements

1. **Match the tone and style** of the example-rfp-sample.md - professional, detailed, confident but not boastful

2. **For sections corresponding to RFP requirements**, structure each as:
   - **The Requirement** - Copy of the original requirement from the RFP
   - **Our Response** - Our answer addressing the requirement
   - **Current State** - Where the feature/capability is at now
   - **Delivery Plan** - Our plan for where it will be once delivered

3. **Incorporate update-notes.md suggestions** where they improve upon the final.md content

4. **Use placeholders** where specific details are still needed (e.g., `[PLACEHOLDER: specific metric]`, `[TODO: confirm with team]`)

## Output

Assemble a cohesive first draft of the complete RFP response, organized according to the template structure but adapted as needed to best address the viaSport requirements.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/source/initial-template-rfp-response.md">
RFP Response Structure Scaffold

Cover Page
• RFP Title: Strength in Numbers Project – B.C. Amateur Sport Information Management System Replacement
• Submitted to: viaSport British Columbia
• Submission deadline: January 9, 2026
• Submitted by: [YOUR COMPANY NAME]
• Primary contact: [NAME, TITLE, EMAIL, PHONE]
• Secondary contact (optional): [NAME, TITLE, EMAIL, PHONE]

⸻

Table of Contents
• [Insert automatic TOC here in Word]

⸻

1. Executive Summary (≤ 3 pages)

1.1 Proposed Solution Overview
[INSERT: 6–12 sentence overview of the platform and what it replaces (BCAR/BCSI)]

1.2 Outcomes / Value to viaSport & Sector
[INSERT: benefits for reporting, analytics, governance, UX, sector collaboration]

1.3 Differentiators
[INSERT: why you vs alternatives; sustainability, extensibility, interoperability]

1.4 Proposed Approach & Timeline (high level)
[INSERT: phases + target go-live + stabilization]

1.5 Budget Summary (high level)
[INSERT: implementation + recurring + options]

⸻

2. Vendor Fit to viaSport’s Needs

2.1 Company Information
• Incorporation date: [INSERT]
• Company size (# staff): [INSERT]
• Locations (HQ + delivery/support): [INSERT]
• Org structure relevant to this RFP: [INSERT]

2.2 Proposed Solution Statement

[INSERT: narrative summary of solution and benefits to viaSport]

2.3 Sector Context and Alignment

[INSERT: understanding of B.C. amateur sport ecosystem, PSOs, reporting obligations, equity needs, data stewardship]

⸻

3. Service Approach and Responsiveness

For each subsection: include approach, key concerns/risks, and schedule alignment.

3.1 Data Submission & Reporting Web Portal

3.1.a UX Strategy and Approach
[INSERT: research, role-based journeys, accessibility, mobile/responsive, usability testing]

3.1.b Technology Stack and Benefits
• Front end: [INSERT]
• Middleware/API: [INSERT]
• Auth/Identity: [INSERT]
• File storage: [INSERT]
• Benefits: [INSERT]

3.2 Data Warehousing

3.2.a Hosting, Tenancy, Data Residency, Regulatory Alignment
[INSERT: cloud, region, tenancy/isolation, residency, PIPA/PIPEDA alignment, SOC2/ISO posture]

3.2.b Backup, Recovery and Encryption Standards
• Backups: [INSERT frequency/retention/testing]
• DR (RPO/RTO): [INSERT]
• Encryption in transit: [INSERT]
• Encryption at rest: [INSERT]
• Key management: [INSERT]

3.3 Data Migration

3.3.a Methodology (mapping, cleansing, validation, rollback)
[INSERT]

3.3.b Audit Trail and Success Verification
[INSERT: logs, reconciliation, sign-offs, sampling]

3.3.c Data Quality Targets/Standards and Defect Workflow
• Data quality targets: [INSERT]
• Defect triage workflow: [INSERT]
• Re-run strategy: [INSERT]

3.4 Platform Design and Customization

3.4.a Cloud Provider Services
[INSERT: services used + rationale]

3.4.b Dev–Test–Prod Workflow
• Environments: [INSERT]
• CI/CD: [INSERT]
• Release management: [INSERT]
• IaC/config management: [INSERT]

3.5 Testing and Quality Assurance

3.5.a QA Approach (performance & security testing)
[INSERT]

3.5.b User Acceptance Testing Strategy
[INSERT]

3.6 Training and Onboarding

3.6.a Audience-Based Training Approach
[INSERT: PSO reporters, org admins, viaSport admins, analysts]

3.6.b Resources and Sample Training Materials
[INSERT: guides, walkthroughs, videos, templates, FAQ]

3.6.c Help Desk and Ticketing Model
[INSERT: channels, hours, response/resolve targets, escalation, KB]

⸻

4. System Requirements Compliance

Use a requirement-by-requirement response matrix so evaluators can score quickly.

4.1 Response Matrix Format

Columns:
• Req ID
• Response (Comply / Configurable / Custom / Partial)
• How requirement is met
• Evidence / where described (section/page/screenshot)
• Notes / assumptions

⸻

4.2 Data Management Requirements Matrix (DM-AGG)

Req ID Response How requirement is met Evidence / where described Notes / assumptions
DM-AGG-001 Data Collection & Submission [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
DM-AGG-002 Data Processing & Integration [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
DM-AGG-003 Data Governance & Access Control [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
DM-AGG-004 Data Quality & Integrity [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
DM-AGG-005 Data Storage & Retention [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
DM-AGG-006 Legacy Data Migration & Bulk Import [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]

⸻

4.3 Reporting Requirements Matrix (RP-AGG)

Req ID Response How requirement is met Evidence / where described Notes / assumptions
RP-AGG-001 Data Validation & Submission Rules [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
RP-AGG-002 Reporting Information Management [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
RP-AGG-003 Reporting Flow & Support [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
RP-AGG-004 Reporting Configuration & Collection [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
RP-AGG-005 Self-Service Analytics & Data Export [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]

⸻

4.4 Security Requirements Matrix (SEC-AGG)

Req ID Response How requirement is met Evidence / where described Notes / assumptions
SEC-AGG-001 Authentication & Access Control [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
SEC-AGG-002 Monitoring & Threat Detection [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
SEC-AGG-003 Privacy & Regulatory Compliance [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
SEC-AGG-004 Audit Trail & Data Lineage [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]

⸻

4.5 Training & Onboarding Requirements Matrix (TO-AGG)

Req ID Response How requirement is met Evidence / where described Notes / assumptions
TO-AGG-001 Template Support & Integration [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
TO-AGG-002 Guided Learning & Walkthroughs [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
TO-AGG-003 Reference Materials & Support [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]

⸻

4.6 User Interface Requirements Matrix (UI-AGG)

Req ID Response How requirement is met Evidence / where described Notes / assumptions
UI-AGG-001 User Access & Account Control [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
UI-AGG-002 Personalized Dashboard [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
UI-AGG-003 Responsive and Inclusive Design [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
UI-AGG-004 Task & Notification Management [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
UI-AGG-005 Content Navigation & Interaction [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
UI-AGG-006 User Support & Feedback Mechanism [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
UI-AGG-007 Consistent Visual Language & Branding [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]

⸻

5. Capabilities and Experience

5.1 Demonstrated Success Delivering Similar Systems

[INSERT: platforms delivered, scale, outcomes, uptime, adoption]

5.2 Partners/Subcontractors (if any)
• Partner name: [INSERT]
• Role/responsibilities: [INSERT]
• Oversight & continuity: [INSERT]

5.3 Relevant Non-Profit / Public Sector / Sport Clients

[INSERT list]

5.4 Case Studies (1+)

Case Study #1
• Client: [INSERT]
• Context: [INSERT]
• Problem: [INSERT]
• Solution: [INSERT]
• Timeline: [INSERT]
• Impact: [INSERT metrics]
• Reference contact (if permitted): [INSERT]

5.5 Automation and/or AI

[INSERT: where automation/AI helps data quality, analytics, UX]

5.6 Responsible AI (if applicable)
• Transparency: [INSERT]
• Privacy: [INSERT]
• Bias mitigation: [INSERT]
• Human-in-the-loop: [INSERT]
• Monitoring/governance: [INSERT]

5.7 Open Standards, APIs, and Open-Source

[INSERT: APIs, standards, data portability, OSS governance]

⸻

6. Project Plan, Timeline, and Delivery Schedule

6.1 Timeline & Milestones Table

Phase Key activities Deliverables Dates Owner (Vendor/viaSport)
[INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
[INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
[INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]

6.2 Governance & Communications

[INSERT: steering cadence, reporting, decision log, escalation]

6.3 Project Team & Roles

[INSERT: PM, tech lead, data migration lead, security lead, UX lead]

6.4 Risks / Assumptions / Dependencies

[INSERT]

⸻

7. Estimated Project Budget and Pricing Model

7.1 Pricing Model Overview
• Implementation (one-time): [INSERT]
• Subscription/managed service (recurring): [INSERT]
• Usage-based components (if any): [INSERT]
• Optional add-ons: [INSERT]

7.2 Cost Breakdown Table

Cost element Description / inclusions One-time Recurring (monthly/annual)
[INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]
[INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]

7.3 Factors Affecting Timeline and Price + Change Management

[INSERT: what triggers changes, how you handle change orders, rate card if relevant]

7.4 In-Kind / Value-Add Contributions

[INSERT: items + estimated value + conditions]

⸻

8. Service Levels, Operations, and Responsiveness

8.1 Support Model

[INSERT: channels, ticketing, escalation, on-call, account management]

8.2 SLAs (template)

Severity Example issues Response target Workaround/resolve target Support hours
[INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT] [INSERT]

8.3 Release and Maintenance Approach

[INSERT: patching, downtime windows, comms, roadmap cadence]

8.4 Data Ownership, Portability, and Exit Plan

[INSERT: exports, formats, offboarding support, deletion/retention]

⸻

9. Security, Privacy, and Compliance

9.1 Canadian Privacy Alignment (PIPA/PIPEDA)

[INSERT]

9.2 Security Controls Summary
• MFA/SSO: [INSERT]
• RBAC/affiliations: [INSERT]
• Audit logs & tamper evidence: [INSERT]
• Encryption: [INSERT]
• Threat detection: [INSERT]
• Incident response: [INSERT]

9.3 Compliance Attestations (if applicable)

[INSERT: SOC 2 / ISO 27001 / equivalent]

9.4 Insurance

[INSERT summary + put certificate in appendix]

⸻

10. Appendices
    • Appendix A — Detailed Requirement Response Matrix (completed)
    • Appendix B — Solution architecture diagrams
    • Appendix C — Data migration plan (sample)
    • Appendix D — Security documentation (policies, SOC2/ISO letter, etc.)
    • Appendix E — Training materials (samples)
    • Appendix F — Case studies & references
    • Appendix G — Resumes / project team bios
    • Appendix H — Detailed pricing worksheets
    • Appendix I — Optional add-ons / value-adds
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/source/VIASPORT-PROVIDED-system-requirements-addendum.md">
# Strength in Numbers System Requirements

**viaSport British Columbia**
409 Granville St #1351
Vancouver, BC V6C 1T2
www.viasport.ca

---

## 1. Introduction

The System Requirements Document captures the complete set of core system-level requirements identified for the Strength in Numbers Information Management System, and serves as the reference documentation throughout the project lifecycle. The System Requirements Document outlines the functionalities necessary to support viaSport's operational requirements for end-to-end data collection, storage, analysis, reporting, and governance.

---

## 2. System Requirements

### 2.1 Data Management

| Req. ID    | Title                               | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                  | Acceptance Criteria                                                                                                       |
| ---------- | ----------------------------------- | ---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| DM-AGG-001 | Data Collection & Submission        | The system shall enable customizable form building, support flexible data entry through variable formats (forms, file uploads), with capabilities for real-time submission tracking, editing, and historical data migration. | Users and System Admin can successfully submit, track, and edit data                                                      |
| DM-AGG-002 | Data Processing & Integration       | The system shall enable standardization of data formatting, logging of transformation processes, and integration with external platforms through API (optional), and data import/export mechanisms.                          | Incoming data is processed uniformly, logged for traceability, and exchanged with external platforms.                     |
| DM-AGG-003 | Data Governance & Access Control    | The system shall enforce role-based access to data and provide administrators with secure database access, along with data cataloging and indexing capabilities for discoverability.                                         | Users can only access data based on permission                                                                            |
| DM-AGG-004 | Data Quality & Integrity            | The system shall ensure relational integrity and continuously monitor data quality using validation rules and automated checks.                                                                                              | Submitted data meets validation rules                                                                                     |
| DM-AGG-005 | Data Storage & Retention            | The system shall support regular backups, disaster recovery mechanisms, data archiving, and secure cloud hosting aligned with retention policies.                                                                            | Data is backed up, archived as scheduled, and securely hosted in the cloud.                                               |
| DM-AGG-006 | Legacy Data Migration & Bulk Import | The system shall provide tooling and configurable mapping templates to import historical data from CSV/Excel, legacy databases, or APIs, including validation, error-handling, and rollback.                                 | Administrators can map legacy fields to system fields, preview results, and execute import; import logs stored for audit. |

### 2.2 Reporting

| Req. ID    | Title                                | Description                                                                                                                                                                                            | Acceptance Criteria                                                                                          |
| ---------- | ------------------------------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| RP-AGG-001 | Data Validation & Submission Rules   | The system shall validate submissions to ensure they are complete, clean, use the correct file types, and contain valid data fields such as dates and contact information.                             | Submissions that fail validation are rejected with appropriate error messages.                               |
| RP-AGG-002 | Reporting Information Management     | The system shall manage metadata related to reporting including but not limited to contribution agreements, NCCP, contact details, fiscal periods, organization profiles, and delegated access rights. | Users can update relevant metadata and access reporting features accordingly.                                |
| RP-AGG-003 | Reporting Flow & Support             | The system shall support automated reporting reminders, allow users to track data resubmissions, and visualize submitted data through dashboards.                                                      | Users are reminded, track changes, and view data in a dashboard format.                                      |
| RP-AGG-004 | Reporting Configuration & Collection | The system shall allow system administrators to configure customizable reporting forms, define required fields, display files for users to read, edit, delete, and download.                           | System admin can configure reporting information and forms                                                   |
| RP-AGG-005 | Self-Service Analytics & Data Export | Enable authorized users to build ad-hoc charts, pivot tables, and export raw or aggregated datasets in CSV, Excel, or JSON (optional) without developer intervention.                                  | User builds a custom chart and exports underlying dataset to CSVs; export respects field-level access rules. |

### 2.3 Security

| Req. ID     | Title                           | Description                                                                                                                                                                                              | Acceptance Criteria                                                                                                         |
| ----------- | ------------------------------- | -------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- | --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| SEC-AGG-001 | Authentication & Access Control | The system shall enforce multi-factor authentication, support secure password recovery, restrict access based on user roles and affiliations, and allow organizational leaders to manage user admission. | Users log in securely; only authorized individuals gain access based on role and affiliation.                               |
| SEC-AGG-002 | Monitoring & Threat Detection   | The system shall detect and flag suspicious activities such as unusual login patterns or behavior anomalies and automatically lock accounts where appropriate.                                           | Security anomalies are flagged, logged, and result in appropriate account safeguards.                                       |
| SEC-AGG-003 | Privacy & Regulatory Compliance | The system shall comply with relevant data protection laws (e.g., PIPEDA) to ensure secure handling, storage, and access to personal information.                                                        | All sensitive data is encrypted and stored securely.                                                                        |
| SEC-AGG-004 | Audit Trail & Data Lineage      | The system shall maintain an immutable audit log of user actions, data changes, authentication events, and administrative configurations, supporting forensic review and regulatory reporting.           | Auditors can filter logs by user or record ID and export results; tamper-evident hashing verifies integrity of log entries. |

### 2.4 Training & Onboarding

| Req. ID    | Title                          | Description                                                                                                                                                           | Acceptance Criteria                                                                        |
| ---------- | ------------------------------ | --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| TO-AGG-001 | Template Support & Integration | The system shall provide a centralized templates tab and offer contextual template access directly from each data entry item to guide users through required formats. | Users can easily locate and access the correct template when needed.                       |
| TO-AGG-002 | Guided Learning & Walkthroughs | The system shall offer onboarding and data upload tutorials to help users navigate key processes, especially during their first-time use.                             | Users can complete tasks independently with support from walkthroughs.                     |
| TO-AGG-003 | Reference Materials & Support  | The system shall provide categorized guides and a frequently asked questions (FAQ) section to help users resolve issues and understand system functionality.          | Users can find accurate answers and instructional material without needing direct support. |

### 2.5 User Interface

| Req. ID    | Title                                         | Description                                                                                                                                                                                   | Acceptance Criteria                                                      |
| ---------- | --------------------------------------------- | --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| UI-AGG-001 | User Access & Account Control                 | The system shall support secure login/logout (MFA), individual and organizational account registration, account recovery, and system administrator account management with role-based access. | Users and system admin can perform account-related tasks securely.       |
| UI-AGG-002 | Personalized Dashboard                        | The system shall provide the capability to create personalized dashboard for each user role, summarizing relevant data, actions, and reporting progress.                                      | Users can view personalized dashboards based on their roles.             |
| UI-AGG-003 | Responsive and Inclusive Design               | The system shall provide a responsive interface across devices and include accessibility features such as screen reader compatibility, color contrast tools, and etc.                         | System is functional on all devices and meets accessibility compliance.  |
| UI-AGG-004 | Communication: Task & Notification Management | The system shall enable automated and customizable notification messages and task reminders that alert users of pending actions and updates, both on the platform and via email.              | Users receive timely and relevant notifications and reminders.           |
| UI-AGG-005 | Content Navigation & Interaction              | The system shall allow users to efficiently locate and interact with information using robust categorization, search and filtering capabilities.                                              | Users can retrieve accurate results through search and filter functions. |
| UI-AGG-006 | User Support & Feedback Mechanism             | The system shall enable users to submit support inquiries and feedback and allow administrators to respond through a managed interface.                                                       | Users can submit and receive responses to inquiries within the system.   |
| UI-AGG-007 | Consistent Visual Language & Branding         | The system shall maintain a consistent design style, color scheme, and branding across all modules.                                                                                           | All UI components follow a standardized visual style.                    |
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/source/VIASPORT-PROVIDED-viasport-sin-rfp.md">
# Request for Proposal

## Strength in Numbers Project

### B.C. Amateur Sport Information Management System Replacement

**December 2025**

**viaSport British Columbia**
409 Granville St #1351
Vancouver, BC V6C 1T2
www.viasport.ca

---

## Overview and Background

viaSport BC Society (viaSport) is an independent not-for-profit organization and a legacy entity of the Vancouver 2010 Olympics and Paralympic Games, operating as the provincial government's lead agency responsible for promoting and developing amateur sport in British Columbia.

For 15+ years viaSport has collected, stored and analyzed a substantial part of BC's amateur sport sector data, enabling informed decision-making, policy development and strategic planning.

Created over a decade ago, viaSport's information management systems are outdated and no longer meet the sport sector's fast-evolving information needs.

viaSport is seeking an experienced technology partner to design, implement, and support a modern, secure, and scalable solution that will transform how British Columbia's amateur sport sector captures, shares, and leverages information – setting a robust digital foundation for the province's next decade of sport development.

viaSport invites technology partners to propose innovative and integrated solutions that advance our reporting, analytics and information-sharing capabilities. Ideal submissions will demonstrate an integrated information ecosystem with automated and advanced analytics, including potential AI-enabled features. We welcome creative solutions that empower users, break down silos, and promote collaboration across the B.C. amateur sports sector.

viaSport welcomes responses from a range of partners, including product companies, data and analytics firms, research and innovation labs, and consortia that combine technology, data science, and sector expertise. Proposals that responsibly leverage open-source technologies, open standards, and interoperable APIs are accepted where they strengthen sustainability, transparency, and sector-wide value.

Beyond replacing legacy systems, this project is an opportunity to create a foundational digital layer for amateur sport in B.C. – a shared data and information platform that will shape how participation, funding, equity, and impact are understood for years to come. We are seeking a partner who can help viaSport responsibly embrace modern data management, interoperable APIs, automation, and AI-enabled insights. The goal is to move from static reports to living, trusted data assets that can power future programs, applications, and innovations across the entire sport ecosystem.

---

## Purpose

We seek an experienced partner who can provide a solution that:

- Is cloud-hosted, modular, and scalable delivered as a managed service (e.g., SaaS or platform-based solution)
- Replaces viaSport's current data collection systems, the BC Activity Reporter (BCAR) and the BC Sport Information System (BCSI)
- Elevates data analytics and reporting to support policy development, reporting compliance, sector evaluation, funding allocations and sport impact assessments
- Enhances the user experience through a convenient, user-friendly, and effective data reporting and submission system for sport organizations
- Improves viaSport's administrative data collection and reporting processes, data warehousing and governance
- Offers sustainability and scalability in cost, maintenance, quality, and function
- Provide innovative, modern and integrated solutions for reporting, analytics, and information sharing needs for viaSport and B.C. amateur sport organizations

---

## Scope of Services

The selected vendor will perform the following services:

- **Data Submission and Reporting Web Portal** – Develop, configure and implement a secure, robust and UX-driven reporting and data submission website portal.
- **Data Warehousing** – Provide data storage/warehousing for viaSport's historical and ongoing data collection, reporting and analytics efforts.
- **Data Migration** – Map, import, and validate historical data from legacy systems.
- **Platform Design and Customization** – Provision cloud environment, security and access model, system architecture, and process automations.
- **Testing & Quality Assurance** – Conduct system security and user acceptance testing; resolve defects.
- **Training and Onboarding** – Deliver training and onboarding resources to the sector and administrator operational hand-off.

### Data Context

- Historical data is 20+ million rows of data
- Growth of approximately 1M rows per year
- Object storage (primarily documents in the hundreds per year)

---

## Expertise Required

- Demonstrated delivery of large-scale SaaS information management platforms
- Proven security and technical expertise in alignment with Canadian privacy statutes (such as PIPA / PIPEDA and SOC II / ISO 27001 or equivalent industry standards)
- Experience migrating legacy data sets and implementing role-based governance
- Experience providing services to B.C. amateur sport sector, Provincial Sport Organizations, or similar non-profit or public organizations
- Familiarity with amateur-sport, non-profit, or public-sector reporting environments (desirable)

---

## Request for Proposal

Proposals should include:

- An executive summary (≤3 pages)
- Estimated project budget and pricing model, with a breakdown of core elements, including factors that would affect timeline and pricing model
- Agency/company/organization profile
- Identification of any partners or subcontractors required and their roles
- One or more case studies and impact of similar work, preferably Canadian NPO / Public Sector clients
- Opportunity to include in-kind services, products or value-add contributions

---

## Proposal Evaluation

Proposals will be evaluated on:

- The fit of the firm to viaSport's needs & sector context
- Quality and feasibility of system solution
- Timeline and delivery schedule
- Capability and experience
- Cost and value of services
- Service levels and responsiveness

Short-listed vendors may be invited to a virtual presentation before final selection.

---

## Evaluation Criteria Details

### Vendor Fit to viaSport's Needs

Details of your company:

1. Incorporation date, company size (number of staff), location, organization and structure as it is relevant to this RFP.
2. A statement of your proposed solution, summarizing the key differentiators and benefits to viaSport for selecting your company.

### Service Approach and Responsiveness

Ability to meet system functions outlined in the system requirements addendum.

Description, key concerns, and schedule alignment of Scope of Services items:

1. **Data Submission & Reporting Web Portal**
   - a. UX Strategy and approach
   - b. Technology stack (e.g., front end, middleware, authentication service) and the benefits

2. **Data Warehousing**
   - a. Hosting solution, tenancy model, data residency and regulatory alignment
   - b. Backup, recovery and encryption standards

3. **Data Migration**
   - a. Detailed migration methodology including mapping, cleansing, validation, and rollback
   - b. Process and tooling to ensure migration audit trail and success
   - c. Data Quality targets/standards and defect-handling workflow

4. **Platform Design and Customization**
   - a. Possible cloud provider services
   - b. Development and customization process (i.e., Development – Testing – Production)

5. **Testing and Quality Assurance**
   - a. Approach and plan to QA (e.g., performance and security testing)
   - b. Approach and strategy to User Acceptance Testing

6. **Training and Onboarding**
   - a. Audience-based training approach and delivery modules
   - b. Available resources and sample training materials
   - c. Help-desk and ticketing model if applicable

### Capabilities and Experience

Provide:

1. Demonstrated success and experience with information management system implementation
2. Identification of any partners or subcontractors needed, their specific responsibilities, oversight mechanisms and continuity of services
3. List of services provided to non-profit, charity, amateur sport sector or public clients
4. One or more case studies of comparable projects – preferably with Canadian non-profit or public-sector clients
5. Description of how the solution uses automation and/or AI to improve data quality, analytics, and user experience
6. If AI is used, approach to responsible AI, including transparency, privacy, bias mitigation, and human-in-the-loop decision-making
7. Use of open standards, APIs, and (where appropriate) open-source components to support interoperability and long-term viability

### Cost and Value of Services

Present:

1. Transparent pricing model
2. Detailed estimation of cost breakdown (e.g., labor, software/licensing, hardware)
3. Factors that would trigger cost adjustments and describe your approach to change management
4. Description and breakdown of any in-kind services, or value-add contributions, and optional add-ons

---

## Contact and Proposal Submission

For RFP questions and submissions, email to: **innovation@viasport.ca**

**Submission Deadline:** January 9, 2026

**Shortlisted vendors will be notified by:** January 31, 2026
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/01-executive-summary/final.md">
# Executive Summary

Austin Wallace Tech is pleased to respond to viaSport British Columbia's Request for Proposal for the Strength in Numbers Project: B.C. Amateur Sport Information Management System Replacement. We believe that British Columbia's amateur sport sector deserves a modern, secure, and purpose-built information management platform that enables informed decision-making, reduces administrative burden, and sets a robust digital foundation for the province's next decade of sport development. That is why we have invested in building a working prototype specifically designed to meet viaSport's requirements.

Replacing legacy systems that have served the sector for over 15 years presents both an opportunity and a risk. The opportunity is to create a foundational digital layer for amateur sport in B.C.: a shared data and information platform that transforms how participation, funding, equity, and impact are understood. The risk is that new system development often encounters delays, cost overruns, and gaps between design and delivery. We have addressed this risk directly by building a functional prototype that already satisfies the majority of system requirements and has been load-tested at production scale with 20.1 million rows of data. This approach significantly de-risks viaSport's decision and demonstrates our commitment to delivering a proven solution, not a promise.

The key highlights of our response are as follows:

**De-Risked Delivery:** We are not proposing to build a system from scratch. A working prototype already exists, purpose-built for viaSport's Strength in Numbers requirements. This prototype has been load-tested with 20.1 million rows of historical data, achieving sub-250 millisecond response times (p95) with zero server errors. The prototype implements the majority of the System Requirements Addendum items today, with the remaining items scoped and scheduled for delivery. This level of pre-existing development significantly reduces delivery risk and accelerates the path to production.

A live prototype environment is available upon request; access details are provided in Appendix A (placeholders until final deployment).

**Domain Expertise:** Austin Wallace, Project Lead, brings a unique combination of enterprise data engineering experience and deep understanding of amateur sport governance. As Chair of the International Quidditch Association, he led data and technology strategy for 30+ national governing bodies worldwide. At the New Jersey Devils (NHL), he served as sole Data Developer, building an end-to-end data platform processing 10 million rows per game of NHL tracking data to support multi-million dollar player decisions. At Clio, he owns 10+ Databricks pipelines and unlocked over $1 million in value through responsible AI enablement. His B.Sc. from UBC in Analytical Sports Management, a custom degree combining business, statistics, and machine learning, was designed specifically for this intersection of sport and data.

Will Siddal, Senior Developer, brings 2+ years of full-stack development experience at Teck Resources, one of Canada's largest mining companies. At Teck, he built mission-critical reporting pipelines processing billions of rows annually, developed internal tools using React and TypeScript, and managed cloud infrastructure on AWS using Terraform. His experience spans the full stack: Python, PostgreSQL, Snowflake, and modern frontend frameworks. Will holds a degree from Simon Fraser University and is based in British Columbia.

**Canadian Data Residency & Compliance:** All data is hosted exclusively in AWS ca-central-1 (Montreal), ensuring compliance with Canadian privacy statutes including PIPEDA. The platform implements encryption at rest (AWS KMS) and in transit (TLS 1.2+), multi-factor authentication with TOTP and backup codes, role-based access control with organization-scoped permissions, and immutable audit logging with tamper-evident hash chains. Audit logs are retained for 7 years with archival to S3 Glacier Deep Archive. AWS maintains a Data Processing Addendum covering all services including SES for email delivery.

**Modern, Sustainable Architecture:** The platform is built on a serverless architecture using AWS Lambda, RDS PostgreSQL, S3, SQS, SES, and CloudFront. This approach eliminates server management overhead, scales automatically to handle peak loads (such as reporting deadline periods), and optimizes costs by charging only for actual usage. Infrastructure is defined as code using SST (infrastructure as code), enabling reproducible deployments, disaster recovery, and full audit trails of infrastructure changes. The technology stack (TanStack Start, React 19, TypeScript, Drizzle ORM, and shadcn/ui) represents 2025 best practices for longevity, maintainability, and performance.

**Our Proposed Solution:**

The Solstice platform delivers a comprehensive information management system designed specifically for viaSport's requirements:

_Data Submission & Reporting Portal:_ A secure, responsive web portal with role-based dashboards for viaSport administrators, PSO reporters, and data stewards. The portal includes a customizable form builder, file upload capabilities, real-time submission tracking, and automated notifications. The interface is built on accessible Radix UI primitives and is tested for performance and usability (Lighthouse metrics available on request).

_Native Analytics Platform:_ Rather than integrating third-party tools such as Metabase or Superset, we built analytics directly into the platform to ensure every query respects tenancy boundaries, every export is audited, and every field-level permission is enforced. Users can build ad-hoc pivot tables and charts, export to CSV, Excel, or JSON, and access self-service analytics without developer intervention.

_Data Warehousing:_ PostgreSQL on AWS RDS provides the analytical backbone, with capacity tested at 20+ million rows and headroom to scale 10x or more. The architecture supports real-time data freshness without ETL delays, multi-AZ failover for high availability, and 35-day backup retention with quarterly disaster recovery drills.

_Migration Tooling:_ Production-ready import infrastructure handles CSV/Excel imports with configurable field mapping, validation rules, preview before commit, and rollback capabilities. Batch processing via AWS ECS Fargate supports large-scale imports with checkpointing for resumability. Migration methodology will be finalized collaboratively based on BCAR/BCSI system capabilities.

_Training & Onboarding:_ In-app guided walkthroughs, a searchable help center with categorized guides and FAQs, a centralized templates hub, and an integrated support request system with status tracking. All training content will be refined through UX interviews with viaSport stakeholders to ensure relevance to actual workflows.

**Proposed Timeline:**

We propose an 18-week implementation timeline from contract signing to full rollout:

| Phase                   | Duration | Milestone             |
| ----------------------- | -------- | --------------------- |
| Planning & Discovery    | 2 weeks  | Requirements sign-off |
| Development & Migration | 6 weeks  | Code complete         |
| User Acceptance Testing | 4 weeks  | UAT sign-off          |
| viaSport Training       | 2 weeks  | Soft launch           |
| PSO Rollout             | 4 weeks  | Full rollout          |

This accelerated timeline is possible because of the extensive prototyping work already completed. Remaining work is refinement, migration, and production hardening, not greenfield development. We acknowledge inherent project risks and commit to early, transparent communication if timeline adjustments become necessary.

**Team:**

| Role                         | Team Member     |
| ---------------------------- | --------------- |
| Project Lead / Data Engineer | Austin Wallace  |
| Senior Developer             | Will Siddal     |
| Security Expert              | TBD (in progress) |
| UX Designer                  | TBD (in progress) |

Austin Wallace, the architect and sole developer of the working prototype, will lead delivery directly. This principal-led approach ensures continuity from prototype through production, eliminates hand-off risk, and provides viaSport with direct access to the person who understands the system most deeply.

---

Austin Wallace Tech welcomes the opportunity to present the working prototype to viaSport and discuss how this solution can serve as the foundation for B.C. amateur sport's next decade of data-driven decision-making. We are prepared to participate in a virtual presentation and demonstration at viaSport's convenience.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/02-vendor-fit/final.md">
# Vendor Fit to viaSport's Needs

## Company Information

### Austin Wallace Tech

Austin Wallace Tech is a British Columbia-based technology consulting firm incorporated in 2025 and headquartered in Victoria, BC. The company was founded specifically to deliver information management solutions to the amateur sport sector, with viaSport's Strength in Numbers project as its primary engagement.

| Attribute     | Details                                     |
| ------------- | ------------------------------------------- |
| Incorporation | 2025                                        |
| Headquarters  | Victoria, British Columbia                  |
| Staff         | 1 principal + contracted specialists        |
| Structure     | Incorporated company with contracted team   |
| Primary Focus | Sport sector information management systems |

Austin Wallace Tech operates as a principal-led consultancy. This structure ensures that the person who architected and built the working prototype will lead delivery through to production. There are no hand-offs between sales, architecture, and delivery teams. viaSport will have direct access to the technical decision-maker throughout the engagement.

### Principal: Austin Wallace, Project Lead and Data Engineer

Austin Wallace brings 9+ years of enterprise data engineering experience combined with executive leadership in international amateur sport governance.

**Professional Experience:**

- **Clio (Aug 2024 to Present):** Data Engineer. Owns 10+ Databricks pipelines processing production workloads on Delta Lake. Unlocked over $1 million in value through AI assistant analysis. Authored company-wide AI best practices guide that increased responsible AI adoption 20x.

- **New Jersey Devils, NHL (May 2022 to Aug 2024):** Sole Data Developer. Built end-to-end data platform processing 10 million rows per game of NHL tracking data, a 10,000x increase in data volume. Developed 40+ dbt models supporting multi-million dollar player salary decisions. Supported 10 analysts and managers.

- **Teck Resources (Oct 2020 to May 2022):** Data Developer. Transformed legacy PostgreSQL stored procedures into testable Python pipelines using Terraform and Azure infrastructure.

**Sport Sector Leadership:**

- **Chair, Board of Directors, International Quidditch Association:** Led data and technology strategy for 30+ national governing bodies across six continents. Oversaw governance, compliance, and information systems for one of the fastest-growing sports worldwide.

- **CEO, Volunteer Media Organization:** Grew organization to 70 staff across 30 countries, managing international coordination and operations.

**Education:**

- **B.Sc., University of British Columbia:** Analytical Sports Management. A custom degree combining business, statistics, and machine learning, including graduate-level coursework. Designed specifically for the intersection of sport administration and data analysis.

**Technical Skills:** Databricks, Snowflake, dbt, PostgreSQL, Python, SQL, Terraform, AWS, Azure, Data Modeling, Batch and Near-Real-Time Pipelines, Responsible AI Enablement.

### Team Member: Will Siddal, Senior Developer

Will Siddal brings 2+ years of full-stack development experience at Teck Resources, one of Canada's largest mining companies.

**Professional Experience:**

- **Teck Resources (2022 to 2024):** Full Stack Developer. Built mission-critical reporting pipelines processing billions of rows annually. Developed internal tools using React and TypeScript. Managed cloud infrastructure on AWS using Terraform.

**Technical Skills:** Python, React, TypeScript, AWS, Terraform, PostgreSQL, Snowflake, modern frontend frameworks.

**Education:** Simon Fraser University. Based in British Columbia.

### Additional Team Members

Security Expert and UX Designer positions are in progress and will be named in the final submission. We expect both roles to be filled with British Columbia-based professionals with relevant enterprise experience.

## Proposed Solution Statement

Austin Wallace Tech proposes the Solstice platform: a purpose-built information management system designed specifically for viaSport's Strength in Numbers requirements.

### Key Differentiators

**1. Working Prototype, Not a Proposal**

A functional prototype already exists, addressing the majority of the System Requirements Addendum items today. This prototype has been load-tested with 20.1 million rows of data, achieving sub-250 millisecond response times with zero server errors. viaSport can evaluate a working system, not a proposal document.

**2. Principal-Led Delivery**

The architect and sole developer of the prototype will lead delivery. This eliminates the risk of knowledge transfer failures between sales, design, and implementation teams. viaSport will work directly with the person who understands the system most deeply.

**3. Domain Expertise in Sport Data**

Austin Wallace's background combines enterprise data engineering (Devils, Clio, Teck) with executive leadership in amateur sport governance (IQA Chair, 30+ national governing bodies). His UBC degree in Analytical Sports Management was designed specifically for this intersection. This is not a vendor who "also does sports." This is a team that understands sport sector data challenges from firsthand experience.

**4. British Columbia Based**

The core team is based in British Columbia; remaining roles are expected to be BC-based (TBD). This proximity supports local context, regulatory alignment, and sector familiarity.

**5. Canadian Data Residency**

All data is hosted exclusively in AWS ca-central-1 (Montreal), ensuring compliance with Canadian privacy statutes including PIPEDA. No data leaves Canadian jurisdiction.

### Benefits to viaSport

- **Reduced Risk:** Evaluate a working system before committing, not a vendor's promises.
- **Accelerated Timeline:** 18 weeks to full rollout because the platform already exists.
- **Direct Accountability:** Principal-led delivery with no organizational layers between viaSport and the technical team.
- **Sector Understanding:** A team that has led amateur sport organizations, not just built software for them.
- **Long-term Sustainability:** Modern architecture (serverless, infrastructure as code) minimizes ongoing operational burden.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/data-migration/final.md">
# Service Approach: Data Migration

## Migration Methodology

### Approach

Data migration follows a phased approach that minimizes risk and allows validation at each stage. The legacy systems (BCAR and BCSI) remain in read-only mode until migration is verified and signed off by viaSport.

### Migration Phases

| Phase                      | Duration  | Activities                                                                                             | Exit Criteria                    |
| -------------------------- | --------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ | -------------------------------- |
| Discovery                  | Weeks 1-2 | Obtain sample exports, document legacy schemas, assess data quality, identify transformation rules     | Schema mapping document approved |
| Mapping and Transformation | Weeks 2-3 | Build mapping templates, define validation rules, create transformation scripts, test with sample data | Mapping templates validated      |
| Pilot Migration            | Weeks 3-4 | Migrate subset (one PSO), validate accuracy, refine mappings                                           | Pilot data verified by viaSport  |
| Full Migration             | Weeks 4-6 | Migrate in sequence: organizations, users, submissions, documents                                      | Reconciliation checks pass       |
| Validation and Cutover     | Weeks 6-7 | Full reconciliation, UAT on migrated data, viaSport sign-off, legacy set to archive                    | Sign-off received                |

### Migration Sequence

Data is migrated in dependency order to maintain referential integrity:

1. **Organizations:** Hierarchy of viaSport, PSOs, and clubs
2. **Users:** User accounts and role assignments
3. **Historical Submissions:** Form data linked to organizations
4. **Documents:** Files linked to submissions

### Mapping Process

Each data type requires a mapping template that defines:

- Source field in legacy system
- Target field in Solstice
- Transformation rules (format conversion, enum mapping, null handling)
- Validation rules (required fields, format checks, referential integrity)

Mapping templates are reviewed and approved by viaSport before migration execution.

### Cleansing

Data quality issues identified during Discovery are addressed through:

- **Format normalization:** Standardize date formats, phone numbers, postal codes
- **Enum mapping:** Map legacy values to new system values
- **Null handling:** Define defaults or flag for manual review
- **Duplicate detection:** Identify and flag potential duplicates for viaSport review

### Validation

Every imported record passes through validation:

- Schema validation (required fields, data types)
- Business rule validation (valid date ranges, referential integrity)
- Format validation (email format, postal code format)

Records that fail validation are logged with specific error messages for triage.

### Rollback

All imported records are tagged with an `import_job_id`. If issues are discovered after import:

- Entire import job can be rolled back by job ID
- Partial rollbacks supported for specific record types
- Legacy system remains available as source of truth until sign-off

## Audit Trail and Success Verification

### Audit Trail

Every migration action is logged:

| Event                    | Logged Information                             |
| ------------------------ | ---------------------------------------------- |
| Import job created       | Job ID, source, target, initiator, timestamp   |
| Mapping template applied | Template version, field mappings               |
| Record imported          | Source ID, target ID, transformation applied   |
| Validation error         | Record ID, field, error type, error message    |
| Rollback executed        | Job ID, records affected, initiator, timestamp |

Logs are stored in S3 and retained for 7 years, consistent with the platform's audit retention policy.

### Success Verification

Migration success is verified through reconciliation:

| Check                 | Method                                             |
| --------------------- | -------------------------------------------------- |
| Row counts            | Source count matches target count (per table)      |
| Checksums             | Hash comparison of key fields                      |
| Spot checks           | Manual verification of sample records by viaSport  |
| Referential integrity | All foreign key relationships valid                |
| Business rules        | Sample queries confirm expected data relationships |

### Sign-Off Process

Migration is not considered complete until viaSport provides formal sign-off. Sign-off criteria:

1. All reconciliation checks pass
2. Spot checks verified by viaSport staff
3. UAT completed on migrated data
4. No blocking issues in defect log

## Data Quality Targets and Defect Workflow

### Data Quality Targets

| Metric                 | Target                           |
| ---------------------- | -------------------------------- |
| Successful import rate | 99%+ of records                  |
| Validation pass rate   | 95%+ on first attempt            |
| Duplicate detection    | 100% of exact duplicates flagged |
| Referential integrity  | 100% of relationships valid      |

### Defect Classification

| Severity | Definition                                            | Response                                     |
| -------- | ----------------------------------------------------- | -------------------------------------------- |
| Critical | Data loss or corruption risk                          | Block migration, immediate resolution        |
| High     | Significant data quality issue affecting many records | Resolve before proceeding to next phase      |
| Medium   | Data quality issue affecting subset of records        | Queue for resolution, proceed with migration |
| Low      | Minor formatting or cosmetic issues                   | Log for post-migration cleanup               |

### Defect Workflow

1. **Detection:** Automated validation or manual review identifies issue
2. **Classification:** Assign severity based on impact
3. **Triage:** Determine resolution approach (automated fix, manual correction, accept as-is)
4. **Resolution:** Apply fix or document acceptance rationale
5. **Verification:** Confirm fix resolves issue
6. **Closure:** Update defect log with resolution

### Defect Reporting

viaSport receives regular defect reports during migration:

- Daily summary during active migration phases
- Detailed report before each phase sign-off
- Final reconciliation report at migration completion

## Technical Infrastructure

### Import Processing

Large-scale imports are processed using AWS ECS Fargate:

| Parameter  | Value                |
| ---------- | -------------------- |
| Compute    | 2 vCPU               |
| Memory     | 4 GB RAM             |
| Storage    | 50 GB                |
| Chunk size | 1,000 rows per batch |

### Checkpointing

Long-running imports use checkpointing for resumability:

- Progress saved after each chunk
- Failed imports can resume from last successful checkpoint
- No need to restart from beginning after transient failures

### Error Handling

- Row-level errors logged to S3
- Error reports include source row, error type, and suggested resolution
- Failed rows can be corrected and re-imported without affecting successful rows

## Dependencies on viaSport

Migration methodology will be finalized based on viaSport's legacy system capabilities. Key questions to resolve during Discovery:

1. **Export format:** Can BCAR/BCSI export to CSV/Excel, or is direct database access required?
2. **Schema documentation:** Does documentation exist for legacy data models?
3. **Data quality:** Are there known issues (duplicates, inconsistent formats) to plan for?
4. **Access:** Who maintains legacy systems and will be available during migration?

Our import infrastructure is production-ready. The extraction approach will be determined collaboratively based on legacy system capabilities.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/data-submission-reporting/final.md">
# Service Approach: Data Submission and Reporting Web Portal

## UX Strategy and Approach

The Solstice platform is designed with a single guiding principle: make data submission intuitive and efficient for non-technical administrators. The platform serves three primary user groups, each with distinct needs:

| User Group              | Primary Tasks                           | UX Focus                                                 |
| ----------------------- | --------------------------------------- | -------------------------------------------------------- |
| viaSport Administrators | Oversight, analytics, compliance review | Cross-org dashboards, audit access, admin tools          |
| PSO Reporters           | Data submission, report tracking        | Streamlined forms, progress tracking, deadline awareness |
| Data Stewards           | Data quality, corrections, imports      | Validation tools, error resolution, bulk operations      |

### Role-Based Portal Design

Each user sees a personalized dashboard based on their role and organizational affiliation. The dashboard surfaces relevant actions, pending tasks, and submission status without requiring navigation through menus.

**Dashboard Elements by Role:**

- **Administrators:** Overdue submissions across organizations, pending access requests, system health indicators, analytics summaries.
- **Reporters:** Current submission status, upcoming deadlines, changes requested, recent activity.
- **Data Stewards:** Validation queues, import progress, data quality exceptions, bulk operations.

### Navigation and Workflow

The platform uses dashboard-led navigation with quick access cards for common tasks. Users can locate information through:

- **Command palette:** Keyboard-accessible search (Cmd/Ctrl+K) for instant navigation to any page, form, or record.
- **Contextual links:** Related actions appear alongside relevant data, reducing clicks to complete tasks.

### Responsive Design

The interface adapts to desktop, tablet, and mobile viewports. All core functionality is accessible on mobile devices, enabling PSO administrators to review and approve submissions while away from their desks.

### Accessibility

The interface is built on Radix UI primitives, which provide WCAG-compliant accessibility by default. This includes:

- Screen reader compatibility
- Keyboard navigation for all interactive elements
- Sufficient color contrast ratios
- Focus indicators for interactive elements

Preliminary Lighthouse accessibility checks indicate strong compliance. A formal WCAG audit is available on request.

### UX Refinement Process

The current prototype provides a solid foundation. During the Planning phase, we will conduct UX interviews with viaSport stakeholders to:

- Validate navigation structure against actual workflows
- Identify pain points from legacy system usage
- Refine dashboard widgets to surface the most relevant information
- Apply viaSport branding and visual preferences

## Technology Stack and Benefits

### Frontend

| Technology     | Purpose                    | Benefit                                                                     |
| -------------- | -------------------------- | --------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| TanStack Start | Full-stack React framework | Type-safe end-to-end, server-side rendering, file-based routing             |
| React 19       | UI library                 | Latest performance optimizations, Server Components, improved Suspense      |
| TypeScript     | Type system                | Compile-time error detection, improved maintainability                      |
| Tailwind CSS   | Styling                    | Consistent design system, rapid development                                 |
| shadcn/ui      | Component library          | Accessible components built on Radix primitives, full customization control |

### Backend and Middleware

| Technology                      | Purpose         | Benefit                                                                  |
| ------------------------------- | --------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| TanStack Start Server Functions | API layer       | Co-located with UI, type-safe, no separate backend service               |
| Drizzle ORM                     | Database access | Lightweight, predictable, generates TypeScript types from schema         |
| Better Auth                     | Authentication  | MFA support (TOTP + backup codes), session management, OAuth integration |

### Database

| Technology            | Purpose            | Benefit                                                            |
| --------------------- | ------------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| PostgreSQL on AWS RDS | Primary data store | Proven enterprise database, tested at 20M+ rows, real-time queries |

### Hosting

| Technology     | Purpose          | Benefit                               |
| -------------- | ---------------- | ------------------------------------- |
| AWS Lambda     | Application tier | Serverless, auto-scaling, pay-per-use |
| AWS CloudFront | CDN              | Edge caching, fast global delivery    |
| AWS S3         | Object storage   | Documents, imports, artifacts         |
| AWS SQS        | Message queues   | Reliable notification delivery        |
| AWS SES        | Email            | Transactional emails, notifications   |

### Analytics

| Technology         | Purpose                | Benefit                                                                   |
| ------------------ | ---------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Native BI Platform | Self-service analytics | Built-in tenancy enforcement, audited exports, no third-party integration |
| ECharts            | Charting               | Interactive visualizations, wide chart type support                       |
| TanStack Table     | Data grids             | Sortable, filterable pivot tables with export                             |

### Why This Stack

This technology combination delivers specific benefits for viaSport:

1. **Type safety everywhere:** Errors caught at compile time, not in production.
2. **Serverless architecture:** No servers to manage, automatic scaling during peak periods.
3. **Accessible by default:** WCAG compliance built into component primitives.
4. **Single codebase:** Frontend and backend in one repository, simpler maintenance.
5. **Canadian data residency:** All AWS services deployed in ca-central-1.
6. **Modern but stable:** 2025 best practices with production-proven technologies.

### Performance Evidence

Lighthouse audit results (latest prototype run; date TBD):

| Metric                   | Score/Value | Target  | Status |
| ------------------------ | ----------- | ------- | ------ |
| Performance Score        | 93/100      | >80     | Pass   |
| Largest Contentful Paint | 2284ms      | <2500ms | Pass   |
| Time to First Byte       | 380ms       | <500ms  | Pass   |
| Total Blocking Time      | 88ms        | <300ms  | Pass   |
| Cumulative Layout Shift  | 0           | <0.1    | Pass   |
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/data-warehousing/final.md">
# Service Approach: Data Warehousing

## Hosting Solution, Tenancy Model, Data Residency, and Regulatory Alignment

### Hosting Solution

The platform is hosted entirely on Amazon Web Services (AWS), using a serverless architecture that eliminates infrastructure management overhead.

| Component        | AWS Service     | Purpose                                 |
| ---------------- | --------------- | --------------------------------------- |
| Application Tier | Lambda          | Serverless compute, auto-scaling        |
| Database         | RDS PostgreSQL  | Managed relational database             |
| Object Storage   | S3              | Documents, import files, audit archives |
| CDN              | CloudFront      | Edge caching, static asset delivery     |
| Message Queue    | SQS             | Asynchronous notification processing    |
| Email            | SES             | Transactional email delivery            |
| Scheduling       | EventBridge     | Cron jobs for automated tasks           |
| Secrets          | Secrets Manager | Credential storage                      |
| Encryption Keys  | KMS             | Key management for encryption at rest   |

### Data Residency

All data is hosted exclusively in AWS ca-central-1 (Montreal, Canada). No data is stored, processed, or transmitted outside Canadian jurisdiction.

| Data Type            | Storage Location        | Region       |
| -------------------- | ----------------------- | ------------ |
| Application database | RDS PostgreSQL          | ca-central-1 |
| Documents and files  | S3                      | ca-central-1 |
| Audit log archives   | S3 Glacier Deep Archive | ca-central-1 |
| Backups              | RDS automated backups   | ca-central-1 |

### Tenancy Model

The platform uses a multi-tenant architecture with organization-scoped access controls. All tenants share the same application infrastructure, but data isolation is enforced at the application layer:

- Every database query is scoped to the user's organization.
- Role-based access control (RBAC) restricts actions based on user permissions.
- Field-level permissions control visibility of sensitive data elements.
- Cross-organization access requires explicit administrative privileges.

This model provides cost efficiency (shared infrastructure) while maintaining strict data isolation between organizations.

### Regulatory Alignment

| Requirement         | Implementation                                                      |
| ------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| PIPEDA compliance   | Canadian data residency, encryption, access controls, audit logging |
| Data minimization   | Configurable retention policies, automated purging                  |
| Right to access     | User data export functionality                                      |
| Breach notification | Audit logging, anomaly detection, alerting                          |

AWS maintains a Data Processing Addendum (DPA) that covers all services used by the platform, including SES for email delivery. The DPA is available at: https://d1.awsstatic.com/legal/aws-dpa/aws-dpa.pdf

### Sub-Processors

| Service              | Provider | Purpose                   | Data Residency        |
| -------------------- | -------- | ------------------------- | --------------------- |
| Cloud Infrastructure | AWS      | Hosting, compute, storage | Canada (ca-central-1) |
| Email Delivery       | AWS SES  | Transactional emails      | Canada (ca-central-1) |

No additional sub-processors are used. All services are provided directly by AWS within Canadian jurisdiction.

## Backup, Recovery, and Encryption Standards

### Backup Strategy

| Parameter                | Value                                          |
| ------------------------ | ---------------------------------------------- |
| Backup frequency         | Continuous (point-in-time recovery)            |
| Backup retention         | 35 days                                        |
| Backup location          | AWS RDS automated backups, ca-central-1        |
| Cross-region replication | Not enabled (single-region for data residency) |

### Recovery Objectives

| Metric                         | Target  | Tested |
| ------------------------------ | ------- | ------ |
| Recovery Point Objective (RPO) | 1 hour  | Yes    |
| Recovery Time Objective (RTO)  | 4 hours | Yes    |

### High Availability

Production environment uses Multi-AZ deployment for automatic failover:

- Primary database instance in one Availability Zone
- Synchronous standby replica in a separate Availability Zone
- Automatic failover in case of primary instance failure
- No data loss during failover (synchronous replication)

### Disaster Recovery Testing

Disaster recovery drills are scheduled quarterly. The most recent drill on file confirmed:

- Point-in-time restore completed successfully
- Application reconnection automated
- RTO achieved within target (4 hours)
- No data loss observed

Evidence available: `/docs/sin-rfp/review-plans/evidence/DR-DRILL-sin-dev-20251230.md`

### Encryption Standards

**In Transit:**

| Protocol | Version | Scope                           |
| -------- | ------- | ------------------------------- |
| TLS      | 1.2+    | All client-server communication |
| TLS      | 1.2+    | All inter-service communication |

**At Rest:**

| Data Type  | Encryption Method | Key Management                  |
| ---------- | ----------------- | ------------------------------- |
| Database   | AES-256           | AWS KMS (customer-managed keys) |
| S3 objects | AES-256           | AWS KMS (customer-managed keys) |
| Backups    | AES-256           | AWS KMS (customer-managed keys) |

**Secrets Management:**

Application secrets (database credentials, API keys, authentication secrets) are stored in AWS Secrets Manager with automatic rotation capability.

### Audit Log Retention

| Log Type               | Retention Period | Storage Tier                                     |
| ---------------------- | ---------------- | ------------------------------------------------ |
| Application audit logs | 7 years          | RDS (recent), S3 Glacier Deep Archive (archived) |
| Infrastructure logs    | 90 days          | CloudWatch Logs                                  |
| Access logs            | 90 days          | CloudWatch Logs                                  |

Audit logs are protected by a tamper-evident hash chain. Each log entry includes a hash of the previous entry, enabling detection of any modification or deletion.

### Why PostgreSQL (Not a Columnar Data Warehouse)

viaSport's data scale (20M historical rows, approximately 1M rows per year growth) is well within PostgreSQL's optimal range. A dedicated columnar warehouse such as Redshift or Snowflake would add unnecessary cost and complexity:

| Factor                        | PostgreSQL        | Columnar Warehouse          |
| ----------------------------- | ----------------- | --------------------------- |
| Optimal scale                 | Up to 500M+ rows  | Billions of rows            |
| viaSport projected (10 years) | 30M rows          | 30M rows                    |
| Operational complexity        | Low (managed RDS) | Higher (cluster management) |
| Estimated annual cost         | $3,000 to $6,000  | $12,000+ minimum            |
| Data freshness                | Real-time         | Requires ETL, often delayed |

PostgreSQL provides excellent analytical query performance at viaSport's scale while keeping data fresh (no ETL delays) and costs low. The architecture supports future migration to analytical extensions (TimescaleDB, DuckDB) if growth significantly exceeds projections.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/platform-design/final.md">
# Service Approach: Platform Design and Customization

## Cloud Provider Services

### AWS Services

The platform is built entirely on Amazon Web Services, deployed in the ca-central-1 (Montreal) region for Canadian data residency.

| Service             | Purpose                                                                     |
| ------------------- | --------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| **CloudFront**      | Content delivery network for static assets and edge caching                 |
| **Lambda**          | Serverless application compute                                              |
| **RDS PostgreSQL**  | Managed relational database                                                 |
| **S3**              | Object storage for documents, imports, and audit archives                   |
| **SQS**             | Message queues for asynchronous notification processing                     |
| **SES**             | Transactional email delivery                                                |
| **EventBridge**     | Cron scheduling for automated jobs (retention, notifications, data quality) |
| **CloudWatch**      | Metrics, logs, and alarms                                                   |
| **CloudTrail**      | API audit logging                                                           |
| **GuardDuty**       | Threat detection                                                            |
| **Secrets Manager** | Credential storage with rotation                                            |
| **KMS**             | Encryption key management                                                   |

### Why AWS

| Factor           | Rationale                                            |
| ---------------- | ---------------------------------------------------- |
| Canadian region  | ca-central-1 provides data residency compliance      |
| Serverless-first | Reduces operational burden, no server patching       |
| Mature services  | Battle-tested, well-documented, strong SLAs          |
| SST integration  | Infrastructure as Code tooling purpose-built for AWS |

### Why Serverless

The serverless architecture provides specific benefits for viaSport:

1. **No infrastructure management:** AWS handles server provisioning, patching, and scaling.
2. **Automatic scaling:** Application scales up during peak periods (reporting deadlines) and scales down during quiet periods.
3. **Cost efficiency:** Pay only for actual compute time, not idle capacity.
4. **High availability:** Lambda automatically distributes across multiple Availability Zones.

### Infrastructure as Code

All infrastructure is defined in TypeScript using SST (Serverless Stack). This approach provides:

| Benefit            | Description                                                                   |
| ------------------ | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Reproducibility    | Any environment can be recreated from code                                    |
| Version control    | Infrastructure changes tracked in git alongside application code              |
| Audit trail        | Full history of what changed, when, and by whom                               |
| Disaster recovery  | Entire stack can be rebuilt from code if needed                               |
| Environment parity | Development, performance testing, and production use identical configurations |

## Development and Customization Process

### Environment Strategy

| Environment | Purpose                           | Infrastructure Tier                               |
| ----------- | --------------------------------- | ------------------------------------------------- |
| sin-dev     | Development and testing           | Minimal (t4g.micro, single-AZ)                    |
| sin-perf    | Performance testing, load testing | Production-like (t4g.large, 200GB)                |
| sin-prod    | Production                        | Full (t4g.large, 200GB, Multi-AZ, 35-day backups) |

Each environment is fully isolated with its own:

- Database instance
- S3 buckets
- Lambda functions
- Secrets
- Domain/URL

### Development Workflow

```
Developer writes code
        ↓
Pre-commit hooks run (lint, type check, format)
        ↓
Automated tests run
        ↓
Code review and merge
        ↓
Deploy to sin-dev (automatic)
        ↓
Deploy to sin-perf (manual, for load testing)
        ↓
Deploy to sin-prod (manual, after UAT sign-off)
```

### Quality Gates

Deployments are gated by standard quality checks:

| Gate          | Tooling                 | Purpose                        |
| ------------- | ----------------------- | ------------------------------ |
| Linting       | Project linting rules   | Code style and error detection |
| Type checking | TypeScript              | Compile-time error detection   |
| Formatting    | Project formatter       | Consistent code style          |
| Unit tests    | Automated unit tests    | Component and function testing |
| E2E tests     | Automated end-to-end tests | Full user flow testing      |

### Deployment Process

Deployments are executed using SST:

```
npx sst deploy --stage sin-prod
```

This single command:

1. Builds the application
2. Synthesizes infrastructure changes
3. Deploys Lambda functions
4. Updates database schema (if needed)
5. Invalidates CDN cache
6. Reports deployment status

### Rollback

If issues are discovered after deployment:

- Previous Lambda versions remain available for instant rollback
- Database migrations are versioned with rollback plans as needed
- SST maintains deployment history for reference

### Customization Capabilities

The platform supports customization without code changes:

| Customization         | Method                                     |
| --------------------- | ------------------------------------------ |
| Branding              | Tenant configuration (logo, colors, name)  |
| Forms                 | Form builder UI for custom data collection |
| Roles and permissions | Admin UI for role management               |
| Notifications         | Configurable notification templates        |
| Retention policies    | Admin-configurable retention periods       |

### Change Management

Changes to the production environment follow a defined process:

1. Change request submitted (by viaSport or development team)
2. Impact assessment (scope, risk, timeline)
3. Development and testing in sin-dev
4. Performance validation in sin-perf (if applicable)
5. UAT in sin-perf
6. Deployment to sin-prod
7. Post-deployment verification

Emergency changes (security patches, critical bug fixes) follow an expedited process with retrospective documentation.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/testing-qa/final.md">
# Service Approach: Testing and Quality Assurance

## QA Approach

### Testing Layers

The platform uses a multi-layer testing strategy to catch issues at different levels:

| Layer            | Tool                     | Purpose                                      | Frequency    |
| ---------------- | ------------------------ | -------------------------------------------- | ------------ |
| Unit/Integration | Vitest + Testing Library | Component and function testing               | Every commit |
| End-to-End       | Playwright               | Full user flow testing                       | Every commit |
| Property-Based   | Custom                   | Access control, audit integrity verification | Every commit |
| Performance      | Lighthouse, k6           | Load testing, Core Web Vitals                | Pre-release  |
| Security         | Manual + automated       | MFA, sessions, audit hash chain              | Pre-release  |

### Automated Testing

Automated tests run on commits and pull requests through the CI/CD pipeline. Merges are gated by passing tests where applicable.

**Test Coverage:**

- Unit tests for business logic and utility functions
- Integration tests for database operations and API endpoints
- End-to-end tests for critical user flows (login, data submission, reporting)
- Property-based tests for access control rules (verifying users cannot access data outside their organization)

### Performance Testing

Performance testing is conducted in the sin-perf environment with production-scale data.

**Load Test Results (latest run; date TBD):**

| Metric              | Value             | Target           | Status   |
| ------------------- | ----------------- | ---------------- | -------- |
| Data volume         | 20.1 million rows | Production scale | Achieved |
| p95 latency         | 250ms             | <500ms           | Pass     |
| p50 latency         | 130ms             | N/A              | Pass     |
| Concurrent users    | 15                | N/A              | Pass     |
| Server errors (5xx) | 0                 | 0                | Pass     |

**Data Distribution:**

| Table                    | Rows  |
| ------------------------ | ----- |
| form_submissions         | 10.0M |
| audit_logs               | 7.0M  |
| notifications            | 2.0M  |
| bi_query_log             | 1.0M  |
| form_submission_versions | 0.1M  |

The platform handles 20 million rows with sub-250ms response times and zero server errors under concurrent load.

**Core Web Vitals (Lighthouse, latest prototype run; date TBD):**

| Metric                   | Value  | Target  | Status |
| ------------------------ | ------ | ------- | ------ |
| Performance Score        | 93/100 | >80     | Pass   |
| Largest Contentful Paint | 2284ms | <2500ms | Pass   |
| Time to First Byte       | 380ms  | <500ms  | Pass   |
| Total Blocking Time      | 88ms   | <300ms  | Pass   |
| Cumulative Layout Shift  | 0      | <0.1    | Pass   |

### Security Testing

Security testing validates the platform's protection mechanisms:

| Area               | Testing Approach                                    |
| ------------------ | --------------------------------------------------- |
| Authentication     | MFA flow validation (TOTP, backup codes)            |
| Session management | Session expiry, concurrent session limits           |
| Access control     | Role-based access enforcement, organization scoping |
| Audit integrity    | Hash chain verification, tamper detection           |
| Anomaly detection  | Login pattern analysis, account lock triggers       |

Security testing is conducted before each release and after any changes to authentication or authorization logic.

### Defect Management

Defects discovered during testing are classified by severity:

| Severity | Definition                             | Response Time |
| -------- | -------------------------------------- | ------------- |
| Critical | Security vulnerability, data loss risk | Immediate     |
| High     | Core functionality broken              | Same day      |
| Medium   | Non-critical functionality affected    | Within sprint |
| Low      | Cosmetic or minor UX issues            | Backlog       |

Defects will be tracked in a shared ticketing system accessible to viaSport.

## User Acceptance Testing Strategy

### UAT Approach

User Acceptance Testing validates that the platform meets viaSport's requirements from the user's perspective. Our UAT approach emphasizes collaboration and early feedback:

| Element       | Approach                                                   |
| ------------- | ---------------------------------------------------------- |
| Environment   | Dedicated sin-perf environment with production-like data   |
| Access        | viaSport testers receive accounts with appropriate roles   |
| Visibility    | Test scenarios mapped to requirements, progress tracked    |
| Communication | Weekly demos, immediate platform access, visible ticketing |

### UAT Timeline

UAT is scheduled for 4 weeks during the implementation timeline:

| Week   | Focus                                                   |
| ------ | ------------------------------------------------------- |
| Week 1 | Core workflows: login, navigation, data submission      |
| Week 2 | Reporting and analytics: dashboards, exports, queries   |
| Week 3 | Administration: user management, configuration, imports |
| Week 4 | Edge cases, regression testing, sign-off preparation    |

### Test Scenarios

Test scenarios are structured around the System Requirements Addendum:

| Category                 | Example Scenarios                                                       |
| ------------------------ | ----------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Data Management (DM-AGG) | Submit form, upload file, import CSV, validate data quality             |
| Reporting (RP-AGG)       | Track submission status, run analytics query, export data               |
| Security (SEC-AGG)       | Login with MFA, verify role-based access, review audit log              |
| Training (TO-AGG)        | Complete guided walkthrough, search help center, submit support request |
| User Interface (UI-AGG)  | Navigate dashboard, use command palette, receive notification           |

### Test Accounts

viaSport testers receive role-appropriate accounts:

| Role           | Access Level                 | Test Focus                                    |
| -------------- | ---------------------------- | --------------------------------------------- |
| viaSport Admin | Full platform access         | Administrative functions, cross-org analytics |
| PSO Admin      | Organization-scoped admin    | User management, reporting oversight          |
| PSO Reporter   | Organization-scoped reporter | Data submission, form completion              |
| Viewer         | Read-only                    | Dashboard viewing, report access              |

### Feedback Process

1. **Immediate access:** viaSport can use the platform at any time, not just during scheduled test sessions.
2. **Weekly demos:** Scheduled sessions to walk through new features and gather feedback.
3. **Visible ticketing:** All issues logged in a shared system where viaSport can see status and priority.
4. **Direct communication:** Questions and concerns addressed within one business day.

### Sign-Off Criteria

UAT sign-off requires:

1. All critical and high-severity defects resolved
2. All test scenarios executed with documented results
3. No blocking issues for go-live
4. Written sign-off from viaSport project sponsor

### Post-UAT

After UAT sign-off:

- Medium and low-severity defects addressed during viaSport Training phase
- Platform deployed to production
- Monitoring enabled for production issues
- Support process activated
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/03-service-approach/training-onboarding/final.md">
# Service Approach: Training and Onboarding

## Audience-Based Training Approach

### Training Audiences

Training is tailored to three primary user groups, each with distinct needs and responsibilities:

| Audience                | Role                                       | Training Focus                                                              |
| ----------------------- | ------------------------------------------ | --------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| viaSport Administrators | Platform oversight, PSO support, analytics | Admin functions, cross-org reporting, user management, system configuration |
| PSO Reporters           | Data submission, compliance                | Form completion, file uploads, submission tracking, deadline management     |
| Data Stewards           | Data quality, imports                      | Bulk imports, validation, error resolution, data quality monitoring         |

### Training Delivery Model

Training combines self-service resources with live sessions:

| Method                     | Audience                    | Format                                    |
| -------------------------- | --------------------------- | ----------------------------------------- |
| In-app guided walkthroughs | All users                   | Interactive tutorials within the platform |
| Live training sessions     | viaSport admins, PSO admins | Video conference workshops                |
| Train-the-trainer          | viaSport staff              | Preparing viaSport to support PSOs        |
| Self-service help center   | All users                   | Searchable guides, FAQs, templates        |

### Training Phases

| Phase                   | Timing      | Participants       | Content                                                             |
| ----------------------- | ----------- | ------------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| viaSport Admin Training | Weeks 13-14 | viaSport staff     | Full platform capabilities, admin functions, PSO support procedures |
| PSO Rollout Training    | Weeks 15-18 | PSO administrators | Core workflows, data submission, common tasks                       |
| Ongoing                 | Post-launch | All users          | New feature introductions, refresher sessions as needed             |

### viaSport Admin Training (Weeks 13-14)

viaSport administrators receive comprehensive training covering:

- Platform navigation and dashboard customization
- User management and role assignment
- Organization hierarchy management
- Analytics and reporting tools
- Import and export functions
- Audit log review
- Support request handling
- System configuration options

Training includes hands-on exercises in the sin-perf environment using realistic data.

### PSO Rollout Training (Weeks 15-18)

PSO training is delivered in cohorts to ensure adequate support:

| Week | Cohort Size              | Support Level                             |
| ---- | ------------------------ | ----------------------------------------- |
| 15   | Approx. 15 PSOs (TBD)    | High-touch, live sessions                 |
| 16   | Approx. 15 PSOs (TBD)    | Live sessions with Q&A                    |
| 17   | Approx. 15 PSOs (TBD)    | Live sessions with Q&A                    |
| 18   | Approx. 15 PSOs (TBD)    | Live sessions, transition to self-service |

**Note:** Cohort sizing and scheduling will be confirmed with viaSport during Planning.

Each PSO training session covers:

- Account setup and login (including MFA)
- Dashboard orientation
- Form completion workflow
- File upload procedures
- Submission tracking
- Help resources and support process

## Resources and Sample Training Materials

### In-App Training Features

The platform includes built-in training resources:

| Feature                 | Description                                                                         |
| ----------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| **Guided Walkthroughs** | Step-by-step tutorials that highlight UI elements and guide users through workflows |
| **Onboarding Tour**     | First-time user experience introducing key platform areas                           |
| **Contextual Help**     | Help icons and tooltips throughout the interface                                    |
| **Progress Tracking**   | Per-user tracking of completed tutorials and walkthroughs                           |

### Help Center

The searchable help center provides:

| Content Type           | Examples                                                |
| ---------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------- |
| Getting Started Guides | Account setup, first login, dashboard overview          |
| How-To Articles        | Submit a form, upload a file, run a report, export data |
| FAQ                    | Common questions organized by category                  |
| Troubleshooting        | Login issues, validation errors, browser compatibility  |

Help center content is searchable by keyword and organized by user role.

### Templates Hub

Centralized repository of templates accessible from the platform:

| Template Type       | Purpose                                                     |
| ------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------- |
| Import Templates    | CSV/Excel templates with correct column headers and formats |
| Form Templates      | Pre-filled examples showing expected data entry             |
| Reporting Templates | Sample report configurations and export formats             |

Templates are linked contextually: users see relevant templates when working on imports, forms, or reports.

### Documentation Formats

Training materials are available in multiple formats:

| Format               | Use Case                            |
| -------------------- | ----------------------------------- |
| In-app (interactive) | Primary delivery, always up-to-date |
| PDF guides           | Offline reference, printing         |
| Video tutorials      | Visual learners, complex workflows  |

### Sample Materials

Sample training materials will be provided to viaSport during the Planning phase for review and feedback. Content will be refined based on viaSport input and UX interview findings.

## Help Desk and Ticketing Model

### Support Tiers

| Tier   | Channel                 | Scope                               | Response                                |
| ------ | ----------------------- | ----------------------------------- | --------------------------------------- |
| Tier 1 | In-app support requests | General questions, how-to inquiries | 24 hours                                |
| Tier 2 | Email                   | Technical issues, bug reports       | 24 hours (standard), 4 hours (critical) |
| Tier 3 | Direct escalation       | Critical issues, system outages     | 4 hours                                 |

### Support Hours

| Coverage        | Hours                                             |
| --------------- | ------------------------------------------------- |
| Standard        | Business hours, Pacific Time (Mon-Fri, 9am-5pm)   |
| Critical issues | Business hours, with monitoring for system alerts |

24/7 support coverage is available as an optional add-on.

### In-App Support System

Users can submit support requests directly from the platform:

| Field       | Purpose                                        |
| ----------- | ---------------------------------------------- |
| Category    | Question, issue, feature request, feedback     |
| Subject     | Brief description                              |
| Description | Detailed explanation with optional attachments |
| Priority    | User-indicated urgency                         |

### Ticket Workflow

```
User submits request
        ↓
Ticket created with unique ID
        ↓
Support team reviews and assigns
        ↓
Response provided (in-app and email notification)
        ↓
User can reply or mark resolved
        ↓
Ticket closed
```

### Response Commitments

| Priority | First Response | Target Resolution (best effort) |
| -------- | -------------- | -------------------------------- |
| Critical | 4 hours        | Same business day                |
| High     | 8 hours        | 2 business days                  |
| Standard | 24 hours       | 5 business days                  |
| Low      | 48 hours       | Best effort                      |

**Note:** Resolution targets depend on issue complexity and may require additional time for root-cause analysis or third-party dependencies.

### Escalation Path

| Escalation Trigger      | Action                                     |
| ----------------------- | ------------------------------------------ |
| Response SLA missed     | Automatic escalation to project lead       |
| Critical issue reported | Immediate notification to development team |
| viaSport escalation     | Direct access to Austin Wallace            |

### Knowledge Base Integration

Common support requests inform help center improvements:

- Frequently asked questions added to FAQ
- Recurring issues documented in troubleshooting guides
- Training gaps addressed in walkthrough updates

### Support Reporting

viaSport receives monthly support reports including:

- Ticket volume by category
- Response time performance against SLAs
- Common issue trends
- Resolution statistics
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/04-system-requirements/data-management-dm-agg/final.md">
# System Requirements: Data Management (DM-AGG)

## Compliance Summary

| Req ID     | Title                               | Status | Implementation                                                |
| ---------- | ----------------------------------- | ------ | ------------------------------------------------------------- |
| DM-AGG-001 | Data Collection & Submission        | Comply | Form builder, file uploads, submission tracking               |
| DM-AGG-002 | Data Processing & Integration       | Partial | Standardization and import/export in place; external integrations scoped with viaSport |
| DM-AGG-003 | Data Governance & Access Control    | Comply | RBAC with org-scoped access, database admin tools             |
| DM-AGG-004 | Data Quality & Integrity            | Comply | Validation rules, automated quality monitoring                |
| DM-AGG-005 | Data Storage & Retention            | Partial | Backups and retention in place; production immutability/archival configuration pending |
| DM-AGG-006 | Legacy Data Migration & Bulk Import | Partial | Import wizard ready; batch worker deployment and extraction scoped with viaSport |

## DM-AGG-001: Data Collection & Submission

**Requirement:** The system shall enable customizable form building, support flexible data entry through variable formats (forms, file uploads), with capabilities for real-time submission tracking, editing, and historical data migration.

**Implementation:**

| Capability           | Description                                                                                                      |
| -------------------- | ---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Form Builder         | Drag-and-drop form creation with field types including text, number, date, select, multi-select, and file upload |
| File Uploads         | Secure file upload with type validation and size limits; stored in S3 with encryption at rest                    |
| Submission Tracking  | Real-time status tracking (draft, submitted, under review, approved, changes requested)                          |
| Edit History         | Full version history with change attribution; users can view and restore previous versions                       |
| Historical Migration | Import wizard supports bulk loading of historical data with field mapping                                        |

**Evidence:** Form submission workflow tested in prototype; submission states visible on user dashboard.

## DM-AGG-002: Data Processing & Integration

**Requirement:** The system shall enable standardization of data formatting, logging of transformation processes, and integration with external platforms through API (optional), and data import/export mechanisms.

**Implementation:**

| Capability             | Description                                                                                          |
| ---------------------- | ---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Format Standardization | Automatic normalization of dates, phone numbers, postal codes during import                          |
| Transformation Logging | All data transformations recorded in audit log with before/after values                              |
| Import Mechanisms      | CSV and Excel import with configurable field mapping, preview, and rollback                          |
| Export Mechanisms      | CSV, Excel, and JSON export with field-level access control enforcement                              |
| Integration Interfaces | Import/export endpoints and data exchange mechanisms; external platform connections to be defined with viaSport |

**Note:** External API integrations (such as connections to third-party systems) will be defined collaboratively with viaSport during the Planning phase based on specific integration requirements.

## DM-AGG-003: Data Governance & Access Control

**Requirement:** The system shall enforce role-based access to data and provide administrators with secure database access, along with data cataloging and indexing capabilities for discoverability.

**Implementation:**

| Capability                | Description                                                                                                       |
| ------------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Role-Based Access Control | Predefined roles (owner, admin, reporter, viewer) with configurable permissions                                   |
| Organization Scoping      | All data queries automatically scoped to user's organization; cross-org access requires explicit admin privileges |
| Field-Level Permissions   | Sensitive fields can be restricted by role; PII visibility controlled at the field level                          |
| Admin Data Access         | Authorized administrators can access data through secure, audited admin tooling; direct database access can be provided if required under a controlled process |
| Data Cataloging           | Metadata cataloging and indexing for forms, submissions, and reports; search capabilities configured with viaSport |

**Evidence:** Role-based dashboards show different content by user role; access control tested via property-based tests.

## DM-AGG-004: Data Quality & Integrity

**Requirement:** The system shall ensure relational integrity and continuously monitor data quality using validation rules and automated checks.

**Implementation:**

| Capability              | Description                                                                                               |
| ----------------------- | --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Relational Integrity    | Foreign key constraints enforced at the database level; Drizzle ORM ensures type-safe queries             |
| Form Validation         | Client-side and server-side validation with Zod schemas; required fields, format checks, and custom rules |
| Import Validation       | Row-level validation during import with detailed error reporting; invalid rows logged for review          |
| Data Quality Monitoring | Scheduled cron job (daily) analyzes data quality metrics; results visible on admin dashboard              |
| Automated Alerts        | Notifications sent when data quality thresholds are exceeded                                              |

**Evidence:** Validation rules active on all forms; import wizard displays validation errors before commit.

## DM-AGG-005: Data Storage & Retention

**Requirement:** The system shall support regular backups, disaster recovery mechanisms, data archiving, and secure cloud hosting aligned with retention policies.

**Implementation:**

| Capability         | Description                                                                             |
| ------------------ | --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Cloud Hosting      | AWS RDS PostgreSQL in ca-central-1 (Montreal) for Canadian data residency               |
| Backups            | Continuous point-in-time recovery with 35-day backup retention                          |
| Disaster Recovery  | Multi-AZ deployment with automatic failover; RPO 1 hour, RTO 4 hours (tested quarterly) |
| Data Archiving     | Audit logs archived to S3 Glacier Deep Archive after 90 days; retained for 7 years      |
| Retention Policies | Configurable retention periods by data type; automated purging per policy               |

**Evidence:** Most recent disaster recovery drill on file; restore verified within RTO target.

## DM-AGG-006: Legacy Data Migration & Bulk Import

**Requirement:** The system shall provide tooling and configurable mapping templates to import historical data from CSV/Excel, legacy databases, or APIs, including validation, error-handling, and rollback.

**Implementation:**

| Capability        | Description                                                                                             |
| ----------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Import Wizard     | Step-by-step interface for file upload, field mapping, validation preview, and commit                   |
| Mapping Templates | Reusable templates for common import formats; viaSport-specific templates to be created during Planning |
| Validation        | Row-level validation with detailed error reporting; records can be corrected and re-imported            |
| Error Handling    | Failed rows logged to S3 with error type and suggested resolution; successful rows committed            |
| Rollback          | All imported records tagged with job ID; entire import can be rolled back if issues discovered          |
| Batch Processing  | Large imports processed via AWS ECS Fargate (2 vCPU, 4 GB RAM) with checkpointing for resumability      |

**Note:** Migration methodology will be finalized collaboratively with viaSport based on BCAR/BCSI export capabilities. The import tooling is ready; production deployment of batch workers and the extraction approach depend on legacy system access.

**Evidence:** Import wizard functional in prototype; tested with multi-million row datasets.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/04-system-requirements/reporting-rp-agg/final.md">
# System Requirements: Reporting (RP-AGG)

## Compliance Summary

| Req ID     | Title                                | Status | Implementation                                                    |
| ---------- | ------------------------------------ | ------ | ----------------------------------------------------------------- |
| RP-AGG-001 | Data Validation & Submission Rules   | Comply | Form and file validation with error messaging                     |
| RP-AGG-002 | Reporting Information Management     | Partial | Core metadata and access controls; program-specific fields configured with viaSport |
| RP-AGG-003 | Reporting Flow & Support             | Comply | Automated reminders, resubmission tracking, dashboards            |
| RP-AGG-004 | Reporting Configuration & Collection | Comply | Form builder, file management, admin configuration                |
| RP-AGG-005 | Self-Service Analytics & Data Export | Comply | Native BI platform with pivots, charts, export                    |

## RP-AGG-001: Data Validation & Submission Rules

**Requirement:** The system shall validate submissions to ensure they are complete, clean, use the correct file types, and contain valid data fields such as dates and contact information.

**Implementation:**

| Capability              | Description                                                                               |
| ----------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Completeness Validation | Required field enforcement; submissions cannot be finalized with missing required data    |
| Format Validation       | Date formats, email addresses, phone numbers, and postal codes validated against patterns |
| File Type Validation    | Uploaded files validated against allowed MIME types; configurable per form                |
| Error Messaging         | Clear, actionable error messages displayed inline; users can correct and resubmit         |
| Server-Side Enforcement | All validation rules enforced on the server to prevent bypassing client-side checks       |

**Evidence:** Validation active on all forms in prototype; rejected submissions display specific error messages.

## RP-AGG-002: Reporting Information Management

**Requirement:** The system shall manage metadata related to reporting including but not limited to contribution agreements, NCCP, contact details, fiscal periods, organization profiles, and delegated access rights.

**Implementation:**

| Capability            | Description                                                                                                             |
| --------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Organization Profiles | Each organization has a profile with name, address, contact details, and classification                                 |
| Fiscal Periods        | Configurable fiscal year settings per organization; reporting periods aligned to fiscal calendar                        |
| Contact Management    | Primary and secondary contacts stored per organization; contacts linked to user accounts                                |
| Delegated Access      | Owners can delegate reporter or viewer access to other users within their organization                                  |
| Metadata Extensions   | Custom metadata fields can be added via form builder for contribution agreements, NCCP, and other program-specific data |

**Note:** Specific metadata fields for contribution agreements and NCCP will be configured during the Planning phase based on viaSport's data dictionary; this is the remaining scope for full compliance.

## RP-AGG-003: Reporting Flow & Support

**Requirement:** The system shall support automated reporting reminders, allow users to track data resubmissions, and visualize submitted data through dashboards.

**Implementation:**

| Capability            | Description                                                                                     |
| --------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Automated Reminders   | Scheduled notifications for upcoming deadlines; configurable lead times (7 days, 3 days, 1 day) |
| Resubmission Tracking | Full history of submissions per form; users can view previous versions and track changes        |
| Status Dashboards     | Role-based dashboards showing submission status, pending actions, and overdue items             |
| Email Delivery        | Notifications delivered via AWS SES; delivery verified in a dev environment (evidence on file) |
| In-App Notifications  | Real-time notification feed within the platform; unread count displayed in navigation           |

**Evidence:** Email delivery tested in dev; scheduled notification processed and delivered successfully (date on file).

## RP-AGG-004: Reporting Configuration & Collection

**Requirement:** The system shall allow system administrators to configure customizable reporting forms, define required fields, display files for users to read, edit, delete, and download.

**Implementation:**

| Capability      | Description                                                                                          |
| --------------- | ---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Form Builder    | Administrators can create and modify forms without code changes; drag-and-drop field ordering        |
| Required Fields | Per-field required flag; validation enforced on submission                                           |
| File Display    | Uploaded files displayed with filename, size, and upload date; preview available for supported types |
| File Operations | Users can read, download, and delete their own files; administrators can manage all files            |
| Form Versioning | Forms are versioned; existing submissions retain their original form version                         |

**Evidence:** Form builder functional in prototype; administrators can create forms and configure field requirements.

## RP-AGG-005: Self-Service Analytics & Data Export

**Requirement:** Enable authorized users to build ad-hoc charts, pivot tables, and export raw or aggregated datasets in CSV, Excel, or JSON (optional) without developer intervention.

**Implementation:**

| Capability     | Description                                                                               |
| -------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Pivot Builder  | Drag-and-drop dimensions and measures; users can create custom pivot tables               |
| Chart Builder  | Bar, line, pie, and other chart types via ECharts; interactive visualization              |
| Export Formats | CSV, Excel (XLSX), and JSON export; exports respect field-level access rules              |
| Access Control | Every query automatically scoped to user's organization; field-level permissions enforced |
| Audit Trail    | All queries and exports logged with user ID, timestamp, and parameters                    |

**Key Differentiator: Native BI Platform**

Rather than integrating a third-party analytics tool such as Metabase or Superset, we built analytics directly into the platform. This approach was chosen after evaluating external tools against viaSport's governance requirements:

| Requirement             | External Tools                          | Native BI                           |
| ----------------------- | --------------------------------------- | ----------------------------------- |
| Tenancy Enforcement     | Requires custom RLS/views per tenant    | Built into query layer              |
| Field-Level Access      | Complex configuration, often bypassed   | Enforced at query time              |
| Audit Logging           | Limited or paid-tier only               | Full integration with audit chain   |
| Canadian Data Residency | Extra configuration for build pipelines | Guaranteed (ca-central-1)           |
| Export Controls         | Often disabled or hard to audit         | Audited with step-up authentication |

This native approach ensures every query respects tenancy boundaries, every export is audited, and every field-level permission is enforced without the complexity and security gaps of integrating external tools.

**Evidence:** BI platform functional in prototype; users can build pivot tables and export data with access controls enforced.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/04-system-requirements/security-sec-agg/final.md">
# System Requirements: Security (SEC-AGG)

## Compliance Summary

| Req ID      | Title                           | Status | Implementation                                        |
| ----------- | ------------------------------- | ------ | ----------------------------------------------------- |
| SEC-AGG-001 | Authentication & Access Control | Comply | MFA, RBAC, step-up auth, org-scoped permissions       |
| SEC-AGG-002 | Monitoring & Threat Detection   | Comply | Anomaly detection, automatic account lock, alerting   |
| SEC-AGG-003 | Privacy & Regulatory Compliance | Partial | Core controls in place; immutability and documentation finalized at deployment |
| SEC-AGG-004 | Audit Trail & Data Lineage      | Comply | Immutable audit log with tamper-evident hash chain    |

## SEC-AGG-001: Authentication & Access Control

**Requirement:** The system shall enforce multi-factor authentication, support secure password recovery, restrict access based on user roles and affiliations, and allow organizational leaders to manage user admission.

**Implementation:**

| Capability                  | Description                                                                                |
| --------------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| Multi-Factor Authentication | TOTP-based MFA with authenticator app support; backup codes for recovery                   |
| Password Requirements       | Configurable password policy (length and complexity)                                      |
| Password Recovery           | Secure email-based reset flow with time-limited tokens                                     |
| Role-Based Access           | Predefined roles (owner, admin, reporter, viewer) with granular permissions                |
| Organization Scoping        | Users are affiliated with organizations; access automatically scoped to their organization |
| User Admission              | Organization owners and admins can invite users, approve join requests, and revoke access  |
| Step-Up Authentication      | Sensitive operations (admin actions, bulk exports) require re-authentication               |

**Evidence:** MFA flow tested in E2E tests; role-based access verified via property-based tests.

## SEC-AGG-002: Monitoring & Threat Detection

**Requirement:** The system shall detect and flag suspicious activities such as unusual login patterns or behavior anomalies and automatically lock accounts where appropriate.

**Implementation:**

| Capability              | Description                                                                               |
| ----------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Login Anomaly Detection | Failed login attempts tracked; patterns analyzed for brute force attempts                 |
| Account Lockout         | Automatic temporary lock after configurable failed attempt threshold                      |
| Anomaly Detection       | Rules-based detection for unusual login behavior and activity spikes; alerts for review  |
| Security Alerts         | Administrators notified of security events via email and in-app notifications             |
| AWS GuardDuty           | Infrastructure-level threat detection for network and API anomalies                       |

**Evidence:** Anomaly detection implemented in `src/lib/security/detection.ts`; account lock triggers tested.

## SEC-AGG-003: Privacy & Regulatory Compliance

**Requirement:** The system shall comply with relevant data protection laws (e.g., PIPEDA) to ensure secure handling, storage, and access to personal information.

**Implementation:**

| Capability              | Description                                                                                      |
| ----------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| Canadian Data Residency | All data hosted exclusively in AWS ca-central-1 (Montreal); no data leaves Canadian jurisdiction |
| Encryption at Rest      | AES-256 encryption via AWS KMS for database and S3 storage                                       |
| Encryption in Transit   | TLS 1.2+ for all client-server and inter-service communication                                   |
| Access Controls         | Role-based and field-level access controls restrict PII visibility                               |
| Data Minimization       | Configurable retention policies; automated purging of data past retention period                 |
| Right to Access         | Data export workflows supported; data subject request process defined with viaSport             |
| Secrets Management      | Application secrets stored in AWS Secrets Manager with rotation capability                       |

**Sub-Processors:**

| Service              | Provider | Purpose                   | Data Residency        |
| -------------------- | -------- | ------------------------- | --------------------- |
| Cloud Infrastructure | AWS      | Hosting, compute, storage | Canada (ca-central-1) |
| Email Delivery       | AWS SES  | Transactional emails      | Canada (ca-central-1) |

AWS maintains a Data Processing Addendum (DPA) covering all services including SES for email delivery: https://d1.awsstatic.com/legal/aws-dpa/aws-dpa.pdf

**Note:** Production immutability controls (e.g., S3 Object Lock for audit archives) will be enabled during deployment, and the final compliance documentation package will be delivered with the production rollout.

**Evidence:** Data residency documented; encryption configuration recorded in infrastructure documentation.

## SEC-AGG-004: Audit Trail & Data Lineage

**Requirement:** The system shall maintain an immutable audit log of user actions, data changes, authentication events, and administrative configurations, supporting forensic review and regulatory reporting.

**Implementation:**

| Capability                | Description                                                                                  |
| ------------------------- | -------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Comprehensive Logging     | All user actions, data changes, authentication events, and admin configurations logged       |
| Immutability              | Audit logs stored in append-only fashion; no modification or deletion permitted              |
| Tamper-Evident Hash Chain | Each log entry includes a hash of the previous entry; tampering is detectable                |
| User Attribution          | Every log entry includes user ID, timestamp, IP address, and action details                  |
| Data Lineage              | Changes to records include before/after values; full history traceable                       |
| Filtering and Export      | Administrators can filter logs by user, record ID, action type, or date range; export to CSV |
| Retention                 | Logs retained for 7 years; archived to S3 Glacier Deep Archive after 90 days                 |

**Evidence:** Hash chain verification implemented in `src/lib/audit/__tests__/audit-utils.test.ts`; audit UI functional in prototype.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/04-system-requirements/training-onboarding-to-agg/final.md">
# System Requirements: Training & Onboarding (TO-AGG)

## Compliance Summary

| Req ID     | Title                          | Status | Implementation                                                |
| ---------- | ------------------------------ | ------ | ------------------------------------------------------------- |
| TO-AGG-001 | Template Support & Integration | Comply | Centralized templates hub with contextual access              |
| TO-AGG-002 | Guided Learning & Walkthroughs | Comply | Interactive tutorials with per-user progress tracking         |
| TO-AGG-003 | Reference Materials & Support  | Comply | Searchable help center with guides, FAQ, and support requests |

## TO-AGG-001: Template Support & Integration

**Requirement:** The system shall provide a centralized templates tab and offer contextual template access directly from each data entry item to guide users through required formats.

**Implementation:**

| Capability           | Description                                                                          |
| -------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| Templates Hub        | Centralized repository of all templates accessible from main navigation              |
| Category Filtering   | Templates organized by type: import templates, form templates, reporting templates   |
| Contextual Access    | Relevant templates linked directly from forms, imports, and reporting screens        |
| Template Formats     | CSV/Excel templates with correct column headers and formatting; sample data included |
| Download and Preview | Users can preview template structure and download in preferred format                |

**Note:** Template content will be refined during the Planning phase based on viaSport's specific data formats and requirements.

**Evidence:** Templates hub implemented in prototype; contextual links active on import and form screens.

## TO-AGG-002: Guided Learning & Walkthroughs

**Requirement:** The system shall offer onboarding and data upload tutorials to help users navigate key processes, especially during their first-time use.

**Implementation:**

| Capability             | Description                                                                                   |
| ---------------------- | --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Onboarding Tour        | First-time users receive a guided tour highlighting key platform areas                        |
| Step-by-Step Tutorials | Interactive walkthroughs for common tasks: submitting forms, uploading files, running reports |
| UI Highlighting        | Tutorial steps highlight relevant UI elements with explanatory tooltips                       |
| Progress Tracking      | Per-user tracking of completed tutorials; users can resume or restart walkthroughs            |
| Contextual Triggers    | Tutorials can be triggered from help icons throughout the interface                           |

**Note:** Tutorial content will be updated based on UX interviews with viaSport stakeholders to ensure alignment with actual user workflows.

**Evidence:** Tutorial framework implemented; guided tour functional in prototype.

## TO-AGG-003: Reference Materials & Support

**Requirement:** The system shall provide categorized guides and a frequently asked questions (FAQ) section to help users resolve issues and understand system functionality.

**Implementation:**

| Capability              | Description                                                                          |
| ----------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| Help Center             | Searchable knowledge base with guides organized by category                          |
| FAQ Section             | Frequently asked questions organized by topic; answers include screenshots and links |
| Keyword Search          | Full-text search across all help content; results ranked by relevance                |
| Role-Based Content      | Help content filtered by user role to show relevant information                      |
| In-App Support Requests | Users can submit support inquiries directly from the platform                        |
| Request Tracking        | Support requests have status tracking; users receive notifications on updates        |

**Help Center Content Types:**

| Content Type           | Examples                                                |
| ---------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------- |
| Getting Started Guides | Account setup, first login, dashboard overview          |
| How-To Articles        | Submit a form, upload a file, run a report, export data |
| FAQ                    | Common questions organized by category                  |
| Troubleshooting        | Login issues, validation errors, browser compatibility  |

**Note:** Help center content will be developed collaboratively with viaSport to ensure it addresses real PSO pain points and common questions.

**Evidence:** Help center implemented; searchable guides and FAQ functional in prototype.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/04-system-requirements/user-interface-ui-agg/final.md">
# System Requirements: User Interface (UI-AGG)

## Compliance Summary

| Req ID     | Title                            | Status | Implementation                                          |
| ---------- | -------------------------------- | ------ | ------------------------------------------------------- |
| UI-AGG-001 | User Access & Account Control    | Comply | Login, MFA, recovery, RBAC, admin management            |
| UI-AGG-002 | Personalized Dashboard           | Comply | Role-aware dashboards with relevant data and actions    |
| UI-AGG-003 | Responsive & Inclusive Design    | Comply | Radix primitives, WCAG-aligned design, Lighthouse metrics on file |
| UI-AGG-004 | Task & Notification Management   | Comply | Automated notifications, email delivery, task reminders |
| UI-AGG-005 | Content Navigation & Interaction | Comply | Command palette, search, filtering, categorization      |
| UI-AGG-006 | User Support & Feedback          | Comply | In-app support requests with status tracking            |
| UI-AGG-007 | Consistent Visual Language       | Comply | Design system with tenant branding configuration        |

## UI-AGG-001: User Access & Account Control

**Requirement:** The system shall support secure login/logout (MFA), individual and organizational account registration, account recovery, and system administrator account management with role-based access.

**Implementation:**

| Capability           | Description                                                                                         |
| -------------------- | --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Secure Login         | Email/password authentication with TOTP-based multi-factor authentication                           |
| Logout               | Secure session termination; session cookies invalidated                                             |
| Account Registration | Individual registration with email verification; organization onboarding via invitation or approval workflow |
| Account Recovery     | Secure password reset via time-limited email token                                                  |
| Admin Management     | System administrators can create, modify, and deactivate user accounts                              |
| Role Assignment      | Administrators can assign and modify user roles within their organization                           |

**Evidence:** Login flow tested in E2E tests; MFA and account management functional in prototype.

## UI-AGG-002: Personalized Dashboard

**Requirement:** The system shall provide the capability to create personalized dashboard for each user role, summarizing relevant data, actions, and reporting progress.

**Implementation:**

| Capability         | Description                                                                            |
| ------------------ | -------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Role-Aware Content | Dashboard displays different widgets based on user role                                |
| Admin Dashboard    | Overdue reporting, pending join requests, system overview                              |
| Reporter Dashboard | Changes requested, submitted reports, upcoming deadlines                               |
| Viewer Dashboard   | Submitted reports, imports in progress, recent activity                                |
| Reporting Progress | Visual indicators for submission status across reporting periods                       |
| Quick Actions      | Common actions (submit form, run report, view notifications) accessible from dashboard |

**Evidence:** Dashboard role-awareness verified via code review; different content displayed by role in prototype.

## UI-AGG-003: Responsive & Inclusive Design

**Requirement:** The system shall provide a responsive interface across devices and include accessibility features such as screen reader compatibility, color contrast tools, and etc.

**Implementation:**

| Capability            | Description                                                                  |
| --------------------- | ---------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Responsive Layout     | Mobile-first design; interface adapts to desktop, tablet, and mobile screens |
| Radix UI Primitives   | Built on Radix UI, which provides accessible components by default          |
| Screen Reader Support | ARIA labels, semantic HTML, and keyboard navigation throughout               |
| Color Contrast        | Color scheme designed to meet WCAG AA contrast requirements                  |
| Focus Management      | Visible focus indicators; logical tab order                                  |
| Tailwind + shadcn/ui  | Consistent, accessible component library                                     |

**Performance Metrics (Lighthouse, latest prototype run; date TBD):**

| Metric                   | Value  | Target  | Status |
| ------------------------ | ------ | ------- | ------ |
| Performance Score        | 93/100 | >80     | Pass   |
| Largest Contentful Paint | 2284ms | <2500ms | Pass   |
| Time to First Byte       | 380ms  | <500ms  | Pass   |
| Total Blocking Time      | 88ms   | <300ms  | Pass   |
| Cumulative Layout Shift  | 0      | <0.1    | Pass   |

**Note:** Formal WCAG audit available on request; platform adheres to WCAG accessibility standards.

**Evidence:** Lighthouse scores documented; accessibility checks performed during QA.

## UI-AGG-004: Task & Notification Management

**Requirement:** The system shall enable automated and customizable notification messages and task reminders that alert users of pending actions and updates, both on the platform and via email.

**Implementation:**

| Capability               | Description                                                                              |
| ------------------------ | ---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Automated Notifications  | System-generated notifications for deadlines, status changes, and administrative actions |
| Customizable Templates   | Notification templates configurable by administrators (scope defined with viaSport)     |
| Email Delivery           | Notifications delivered via AWS SES to user's email address                              |
| In-App Notifications     | Real-time notification feed; unread count displayed in navigation bar                    |
| Task Reminders           | Configurable reminder schedules (7 days, 3 days, 1 day before deadline)                  |
| Notification Preferences | Notification preferences configurable by role (scope defined with viaSport)             |

**Evidence:** Email delivery verified in dev; in-app notifications functional in prototype (date on file).

## UI-AGG-005: Content Navigation & Interaction

**Requirement:** The system shall allow users to efficiently locate and interact with information using robust categorization, search and filtering capabilities.

**Implementation:**

| Capability      | Description                                                                            |
| --------------- | -------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Command Palette | Keyboard-accessible search (Cmd+K / Ctrl+K) for quick navigation to any page or action |
| Search          | Search within lists and records; global search can be enabled as needed               |
| Filtering       | Multi-criteria filtering on list views                                                |
| Categorization  | Content organized by type, organization, status, and date                              |
| Pagination      | Large datasets paginated for performance; configurable page size                       |
| Sorting         | Column-based sorting on all tabular data                                               |

**Evidence:** Command palette and list filtering functional in prototype; search capabilities available where enabled.

## UI-AGG-006: User Support & Feedback

**Requirement:** The system shall enable users to submit support inquiries and feedback and allow administrators to respond through a managed interface.

**Implementation:**

| Capability           | Description                                                                  |
| -------------------- | ---------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Support Request Form | In-app form for submitting questions, issues, feature requests, and feedback |
| Category Selection   | Users categorize requests for efficient routing                              |
| Status Tracking      | Requests have status (submitted, in progress, resolved); users see updates   |
| Admin Interface      | Administrators can view, respond to, and resolve support requests            |
| Email Notifications  | Users notified via email when their request receives a response              |

**Evidence:** Support request workflow implemented in prototype; status tracking functional.

## UI-AGG-007: Consistent Visual Language & Branding

**Requirement:** The system shall maintain a consistent design style, color scheme, and branding across all modules.

**Implementation:**

| Capability         | Description                                                         |
| ------------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Design System      | Unified component library via shadcn/ui ensures visual consistency  |
| Color Scheme       | Configurable color palette applied consistently across all modules  |
| Typography         | Consistent font family, sizes, and weights throughout the interface |
| Tenant Branding    | Configurable logo, primary colors, and organization name per tenant |
| Icon Library       | Consistent iconography across the interface                         |
| Spacing and Layout | Standardized spacing scale and layout patterns across all screens   |

**Note:** viaSport-specific branding (logo, colors) will be configured during the Planning phase.

**Evidence:** Design system applied consistently across prototype; branding configuration available in admin settings.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/05-capabilities-experience/final.md">
# Capabilities and Experience

## Demonstrated Success Delivering Similar Systems

Austin Wallace Tech brings demonstrated experience delivering enterprise-scale information management systems across sports and data-intensive industries.

### Austin Wallace: Enterprise Data Engineering

| Organization                              | Role                | Achievements                                                                                                                                                                                                 |
| ----------------------------------------- | ------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| **Clio** (2024 to Present)                | Data Engineer       | Owns 10+ Databricks pipelines processing production workloads. Unlocked $1M+ in value through AI analysis. Authored company-wide AI best practices guide, increasing responsible AI adoption 20x.            |
| **New Jersey Devils, NHL** (2022 to 2024) | Sole Data Developer | Built end-to-end data platform processing 10 million rows per game of NHL tracking data (10,000x increase in data volume). Developed 40+ dbt models supporting multi-million dollar player salary decisions. |
| **Teck Resources** (2020 to 2022)         | Data Developer      | Transformed legacy PostgreSQL stored procedures into testable Python pipelines using Terraform and Azure infrastructure.                                                                                     |

### Will Siddal: Full-Stack Development

| Organization                      | Role                 | Achievements                                                                                                                                                                               |
| --------------------------------- | -------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| **Teck Resources** (2022 to 2024) | Full Stack Developer | Built mission-critical reporting pipelines processing billions of rows annually. Developed internal tools using React and TypeScript. Managed cloud infrastructure on AWS using Terraform. |

### The Solstice Prototype as Proof of Capability

The most relevant demonstration of our capability is the Solstice platform itself: a working prototype built specifically for viaSport's Strength in Numbers requirements.

| Metric           | Value                                       |
| ---------------- | ------------------------------------------- |
| Codebase         | 20,000+ lines of tested TypeScript          |
| Requirements Met | Majority of system requirements implemented; remaining items scoped |
| Load Testing     | 20.1 million rows, sub-250ms response times |
| Server Errors    | Zero under concurrent load                  |

This is not a theoretical proposal. viaSport can evaluate a working system.

## Partners and Subcontractors

### Team Structure

| Role                     | Team Member     | Responsibilities                                                       | Status    |
| ------------------------ | --------------- | ---------------------------------------------------------------------- | --------- |
| Project Lead / Architect | Austin Wallace  | Architecture, data engineering, project management, delivery oversight | Committed |
| Senior Developer         | Will Siddal     | Frontend/backend development, feature implementation                   | Committed |
| Security Expert          | TBD             | Security review, penetration testing, compliance validation            | In progress |
| UX Designer              | TBD             | User research, interface design, accessibility audit                   | In progress |

The core team is based in British Columbia; remaining roles are expected to be BC-based (TBD).

### Oversight Mechanisms

Austin Wallace, as Project Lead, maintains direct oversight of all project work:

- **Daily coordination** with development team on implementation priorities
- **Weekly deliverable reviews** with full team
- **Code review requirements** for all changes before merge
- **Security sign-off** required for authentication and access control changes
- **Direct accountability** to viaSport with no organizational layers in between

### Continuity of Services

The architecture and deployment approach ensures continuity regardless of team changes:

- **Infrastructure as Code**: All AWS resources defined in SST, reproducible from version control
- **Comprehensive Documentation**: Architecture decisions, deployment procedures, and operational runbooks maintained in the repository
- **Automated Testing**: CI validates core workflows and regressions on each change
- **Operational Runbooks**: Environment setup, deployment, and recovery procedures documented for continuity

In the event of team member departure, knowledge transfer is supported by the codebase itself. The principal-led structure ensures Austin Wallace remains the constant point of accountability.

## Relevant Non-Profit, Public Sector, and Sport Clients

### Direct Sport Sector Experience

| Organization                            | Relationship              | Scope                                                                                                                                                                                                          |
| --------------------------------------- | ------------------------- | -------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| **International Quidditch Association** | Chair, Board of Directors | Led governance, data, and technology strategy for 30+ national governing bodies across six continents. Managed compliance, reporting, and information systems for one of the fastest-growing sports worldwide. |
| **Volunteer Media Organization**        | CEO                       | Grew organization to 70 staff across 30 countries. Managed international coordination, operations, and communications infrastructure.                                                                          |

This is not vendor experience serving the sport sector from the outside. Austin Wallace has led amateur sport organizations from the inside, understanding the governance challenges, resource constraints, and stakeholder dynamics that viaSport navigates daily.

### Team Experience with Public Sector and Enterprise Clients

| Team Member    | Organization            | Sector                                                         |
| -------------- | ----------------------- | -------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Austin Wallace | Teck Resources          | Resource sector, publicly traded                               |
| Austin Wallace | New Jersey Devils (NHL) | Professional sports                                            |
| Austin Wallace | Clio                    | Legal technology (serves law firms, including public interest) |
| Will Siddal    | Teck Resources          | Resource sector, publicly traded                               |

## Case Studies

### Primary: Solstice Platform (for viaSport)

**Context:** viaSport issued an RFP to replace legacy information management systems (BCAR and BCSI) serving 60+ Provincial Sport Organizations. The RFP specified 25 system requirements across data management, reporting, security, training, and user interface.

**Approach:** Rather than responding with a proposal document, Austin Wallace Tech built a working prototype that demonstrates capability through a functioning system.

**Deliverables:**

| Component               | Description                                                             |
| ----------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Data Submission Portal  | Form builder, file uploads, submission tracking, version history        |
| Native BI Platform      | Pivot tables, charts, export to CSV/Excel/JSON with tenancy enforcement |
| Role-Based Access       | Organization-scoped permissions, field-level access control             |
| Security Infrastructure | MFA, anomaly detection, tamper-evident audit logs                       |
| Import Tooling          | CSV/Excel import with mapping, validation, preview, rollback            |
| Training Framework      | Guided walkthroughs, help center, templates hub                         |

**Results:**

- Majority of system requirements addressed; remaining items scheduled in the implementation plan
- Load tested with 20.1 million rows
- Sub-250ms response times (p95) under concurrent load
- Zero server errors
- Live prototype available for viaSport evaluation

### Supporting: Qdrill (Production Sports Application)

**Context:** A training application used by competitive athletes, including members of Team Canada.

**Scope:** 87,000+ lines of code. Full-stack application with user authentication, data persistence, and real-time features.

**Relevance:** Demonstrates ability to ship user-facing sports software to production with real users and real data.

### Supporting: New Jersey Devils Data Platform

**Context:** The NHL requires teams to process large volumes of tracking data for player evaluation and game strategy.

**Scope:** 10 million rows per game. 40+ dbt models. Supported multi-million dollar player salary decisions.

**Relevance:** Demonstrates enterprise-scale data engineering in a sports context, with high stakes for data accuracy and reliability.

## Automation and AI

### Automation (Production-Ready)

The platform includes comprehensive automation for operational efficiency:

| Feature                 | Schedule        | Purpose                                                            |
| ----------------------- | --------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| Scheduled Notifications | Every 5 minutes | Process queued notifications, send email digests                   |
| Retention Enforcement   | Daily           | Purge data past retention period, archive audit logs to S3 Glacier |
| Data Quality Monitor    | Daily           | Scan submissions for completeness, flag data quality issues        |
| Notification Queue      | Event-driven    | Asynchronous email delivery with retry and dead-letter queue       |
| Batch Import Worker     | On-demand       | Process large CSV/Excel imports via ECS Fargate with checkpointing |
| Health Monitoring       | On-demand       | Database and service health checks with alerting                   |
| Audit Logging           | Real-time       | Immutable logging of all system actions                            |

**Technical Infrastructure:**

| Service         | Purpose                                            |
| --------------- | -------------------------------------------------- |
| AWS EventBridge | Cron scheduling for periodic jobs                  |
| AWS Lambda      | Serverless job execution                           |
| AWS SQS FIFO    | Notification queue with deduplication              |
| AWS ECS Fargate | Batch processing (2 vCPU, 4 GB RAM, checkpointing) |
| AWS SES         | Email delivery with bounce handling                |
| AWS CloudWatch  | Metrics, alarms, and centralized logging           |

### AI Features (Roadmap)

The platform architecture is AI-ready, with specific features to be prioritized in collaboration with viaSport during the Planning phase.

**Proposed AI Features for Year 1:**

| Feature                | Description                                                 | Benefit                                        |
| ---------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------- | ---------------------------------------------- |
| AI Report Narratives   | Generate board-ready summaries from submitted data          | Reduce manual report writing                   |
| Natural Language Query | Ask questions about data in plain English                   | Self-service analytics for non-technical users |
| Data Quality AI        | Automatically detect anomalies and errors in submissions    | Improve data integrity                         |
| Submission Assistant   | Help PSOs complete forms correctly with contextual guidance | Reduce errors and support requests             |

**Why AI is Roadmap, Not Day-One:**

The RFP identifies AI-enabled features as desirable, not required. Our approach prioritizes:

1. Delivering core functionality first
2. Gathering real usage data to inform AI priorities
3. Collaborating with viaSport to identify highest-value AI applications
4. Implementing AI features with proper validation and testing

Austin Wallace's experience at Clio (authored company-wide AI best practices, achieved 20x increase in responsible AI adoption) informs this measured approach.

## Responsible AI Approach

When AI features are implemented, the following principles will govern their development and deployment:

### Transparency

- Clear indication when AI generates or assists with content
- Explanation of AI confidence levels where applicable
- Documentation of AI model sources and capabilities

### Human-in-the-Loop

- AI-generated reports require human review before publication
- AI suggestions are recommendations, not automatic actions
- Users can override or reject AI outputs

### Privacy Protection

- AI models do not train on viaSport data without explicit consent
- PII is excluded from AI processing where not essential
- AI features respect the same access controls as the rest of the platform

### Bias Awareness

- Regular review of AI outputs for unintended patterns
- Diverse test cases during AI feature development
- Feedback mechanisms for users to flag problematic outputs

## Open Standards, APIs, and Open Source

### Open Standards

| Standard        | Usage                          |
| --------------- | ------------------------------ |
| TOTP (RFC 6238) | Multi-factor authentication    |
| CSV/Excel       | Data import and export formats |
| JSON            | Data interchange               |
| TLS 1.2+        | Transport security             |
| AES-256         | Encryption at rest             |

### APIs

The platform provides internal APIs and integration points. External APIs and webhooks can be exposed as needed and scoped collaboratively with viaSport during Planning.

**Note:** Integration requirements (e.g., third-party databases or services) will be defined with viaSport before implementation.

### Open Source

The platform is built on industry-standard open source technologies:

| Layer          | Technologies                                                     |
| -------------- | ---------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Frontend       | React 19, TanStack Start, TypeScript, Radix UI, Tailwind CSS      |
| Backend        | TanStack Start, Node.js, Drizzle ORM                             |
| Database       | PostgreSQL                                                       |
| Infrastructure | SST (infrastructure as code)                                     |
| Testing        | Vitest, Playwright, Testing Library                              |
| Validation     | Zod                                                              |

This open source foundation ensures:

- **No vendor lock-in** for core technologies
- **Community support** and ongoing development
- **Auditability** of underlying code
- **Portability** if future migration is needed
- **Talent availability** for future development

The application code itself is proprietary, owned by Austin Wallace Tech, with full source code access provided to viaSport as part of the engagement.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/06-cost-value/final.md">
# Cost and Value of Services

## Pricing Model Overview

Austin Wallace Tech proposes a fixed-price engagement with transparent pricing and milestone-based payments.

| Component         | Amount   | Period   |
| ----------------- | -------- | -------- |
| Implementation    | $600,000 | One-time |
| Annual Operations | $200,000 | Per year |

**Year 1 Total:** $800,000
**Year 2+ Total:** $200,000 per year

This pricing reflects the value delivered to viaSport, not cost-plus billing. The working prototype significantly de-risks this engagement: viaSport is paying for a proven solution adapted to their needs, not greenfield development.

## Cost Breakdown

### Implementation ($600,000)

| Phase                   | Activities                                                        |
| ----------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Planning & Discovery    | Requirements validation, UX interviews, migration planning        |
| Development             | Remaining feature work, viaSport-specific configuration, branding |
| Data Migration          | Legacy data extraction, mapping, validation, import               |
| User Acceptance Testing | UAT environment, test support, defect resolution                  |
| Training                | viaSport administrator training, train-the-trainer sessions       |
| PSO Rollout             | Cohort-based PSO onboarding, go-live support                      |
| Production Deployment   | Production environment configuration, monitoring setup            |

All RFP requirements (DM-AGG, RP-AGG, SEC-AGG, TO-AGG, UI-AGG) are included, including completion of the remaining gaps identified in this draft.

### Annual Operations ($200,000/year)

| Category                 | Scope                                                            |
| ------------------------ | ---------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Hosting & Infrastructure | AWS ca-central-1, Multi-AZ database, CDN, storage, compute       |
| Security                 | Ongoing monitoring, security patches, quarterly security reviews |
| Maintenance              | Bug fixes, dependency updates, performance optimization          |
| Support                  | Business hours support (24h response standard, 4h critical)      |
| Minor Enhancements       | Small improvements within existing feature scope                 |
| Disaster Recovery        | Maintained backups, quarterly DR drills                          |

### Payment Schedule

| Milestone        | Percentage | Amount   | Trigger                          |
| ---------------- | ---------- | -------- | -------------------------------- |
| Contract Signing | 25%        | $150,000 | Signed agreement                 |
| UAT Sign-Off     | 25%        | $150,000 | User acceptance testing complete |
| Go-Live          | 50%        | $300,000 | Production deployment            |

Annual operations billed quarterly in advance ($50,000 per quarter).

## Factors Affecting Timeline and Price

### Scope Changes

Changes to scope beyond the RFP requirements would trigger a change order process:

| Change Type                  | Process                                               |
| ---------------------------- | ----------------------------------------------------- |
| New features not in RFP      | Scope assessment, proposal, mutual agreement          |
| Additional integrations      | Integration specification, impact assessment, pricing |
| Major infrastructure changes | Architecture review, proposal with options            |

The change management process ensures no work begins without mutual agreement on scope, timeline, and cost.

### Change Management Process

1. Change request submitted (by either party)
2. Impact assessment (scope, timeline, cost implications)
3. Proposal with options presented
4. Mutual agreement documented
5. Work proceeds only after sign-off

### Factors That Would NOT Trigger Price Adjustments

- Normal data volume growth within PostgreSQL capacity (tested to 20M+ rows, with headroom for projected growth)
- Reasonable support request volume
- Standard security updates and patches
- Configuration changes within existing features

## Optional Add-Ons

### Operations Portal (Events & Team Management)

**Estimated:** $50,000 to $100,000 implementation, plus ongoing support

The Solstice platform includes an operations portal (currently deployed for Quadball Canada) that enables event registration, team management, and membership features. This could be extended to viaSport and PSOs.

**Potential Value:**

- Single source of truth: reporting and operations in one system
- Reduced duplicate data entry for PSOs
- Better analytics: participation data linked to reporting
- Faster compliance: reporting validated against real event data

**Considerations:**

- Expands user base beyond reporters (players, parents, club admins)
- Increases support volume
- Requires scoping discussion to define exact requirements

This is offered as an option, not included in the base proposal.

### Extended Support Coverage (24/7)

**Estimated:** $30,000 to $50,000 per year additional

Standard support covers business hours (Monday to Friday, 9am to 5pm Pacific). Extended coverage would add:

- After-hours monitoring and response
- Critical issue escalation outside business hours
- Weekend and holiday coverage

This would be delivered via subcontractor arrangement.

## In-Kind and Value-Add Contributions

### Value-Add: Working Prototype

The most significant value-add is the working prototype itself. Rather than proposing to build a system, Austin Wallace Tech has already built one:

- 20,000+ lines of tested TypeScript
- Majority of system requirements addressed; remaining items scheduled in the implementation plan
- Load tested with 20.1 million rows
- Available for viaSport evaluation before contract signing

This represents substantial pre-investment that de-risks the engagement for viaSport.

### Value-Add: Source Code Access

Source code access can be provided under mutually agreed terms (e.g., escrow or direct access). This supports:

- Transparency: viaSport can audit the code at any time
- Continuity: If the engagement ends, viaSport retains access to the codebase
- Flexibility: Future development can be performed by any qualified team

### Pricing Philosophy

This pricing represents our best honest value. We do not inflate prices to offer discounts during negotiation. The figures above reflect:

- Efficient modern development practices
- Substantial pre-built functionality (prototype)
- Lean team without enterprise overhead
- Value-based pricing tied to outcomes, not hourly billing

Traditional government IT projects of comparable scope often run $1 to $2 million or more. Our pricing reflects the efficiency of a working prototype and a principal-led delivery model.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/07-delivery-schedule/final.md">
# Project Plan, Timeline, and Delivery Schedule

## Timeline and Milestones

Austin Wallace Tech proposes an 18-week implementation timeline from contract signing to full rollout.

| Phase                   | Duration | Key Activities                                              | Milestone             |
| ----------------------- | -------- | ----------------------------------------------------------- | --------------------- |
| Planning & Discovery    | 2 weeks  | UX interviews, requirements refinement, migration discovery | Requirements Sign-Off |
| Development & Migration | 6 weeks  | Feature refinement, viaSport configuration, data migration  | Code Complete         |
| User Acceptance Testing | 4 weeks  | viaSport testing, defect resolution, acceptance sign-off    | UAT Sign-Off          |
| viaSport Training       | 2 weeks  | Admin training, documentation handoff, support preparation  | Soft Launch           |
| PSO Rollout             | 4 weeks  | PSO onboarding, tiered training, support ramp-up            | Full Rollout          |

**Total Duration:** 18 weeks

### Why This Timeline is Achievable

Traditional information management system implementations of this scope typically require 24 to 36 weeks. Our accelerated timeline is possible because the working prototype already addresses the majority of system requirements:

| Traditional Phase         | Status   | Remaining Work                       |
| ------------------------- | -------- | ------------------------------------ |
| Architecture              | Complete | None                                 |
| Authentication & Security | Complete | Production hardening                 |
| Core Features             | ~90% complete | UX refinements per viaSport feedback |
| Analytics Platform        | Complete | None                                 |
| Migration Tooling         | Complete | Extraction depends on legacy systems |

Remaining work is refinement and migration, not greenfield development.

### Phase Details

**Planning & Discovery (Weeks 1-2)**

- Kickoff meeting and project plan confirmation
- UX interviews with viaSport stakeholders
- Requirements validation against prototype
- Migration discovery (legacy system access, schema documentation)
- Brand asset collection (logo, colors, style guidelines)

**Development & Migration (Weeks 3-8)**

- viaSport-specific configuration and branding
- UX refinements based on interview findings
- Legacy data extraction and mapping
- Data migration with validation
- Production environment preparation

**User Acceptance Testing (Weeks 9-12)**

- UAT environment with production-like data
- viaSport test scenarios executed
- Defect identification and resolution
- Performance validation
- Security review

**viaSport Training (Weeks 13-14)**

- Administrator training sessions
- Train-the-trainer preparation
- Documentation and runbook handoff
- Support process activation
- **Soft Launch:** viaSport administrators active on platform

**PSO Rollout (Weeks 15-18)**

- Cohort-based PSO onboarding (approx. 15 PSOs per week, TBD with viaSport)
- Live training sessions with Q&A
- Support ramp-up and monitoring
- Legacy systems archived
- **Full Rollout:** All 60 PSOs onboarded

## Governance and Communications

### Communication Cadence

| Frequency | Participants                              | Purpose                                            |
| --------- | ----------------------------------------- | -------------------------------------------------- |
| Weekly    | Austin Wallace + viaSport Project Manager | Status updates, blockers, decisions                |
| Bi-weekly | Steering committee                        | Milestone review, escalations, strategic decisions |
| As needed | Technical stakeholders                    | Deep-dives, UX reviews, migration planning         |

### Reporting

viaSport will receive:

- Weekly status reports summarizing progress, risks, and upcoming work
- Milestone completion reports with deliverable sign-off
- Defect status reports during UAT
- Post-go-live support reports (monthly)

### Decision-Making

| Decision Type              | Authority                               |
| -------------------------- | --------------------------------------- |
| Day-to-day implementation  | Austin Wallace (Project Lead)           |
| Requirements clarification | viaSport Project Manager                |
| Scope changes              | Mutual agreement (change order process) |
| Go-live readiness          | viaSport Project Sponsor                |

## Project Team and Roles

| Role                     | Team Member     | Responsibilities                                                     |
| ------------------------ | --------------- | -------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Project Lead / Architect | Austin Wallace  | Architecture, delivery oversight, viaSport liaison, data engineering |
| Senior Developer         | Will Siddal     | Feature development, bug fixes, frontend implementation              |
| Security Expert          | TBD (in progress) | Security review, penetration testing, compliance validation        |
| UX Designer              | TBD (in progress) | User research, interface refinement, accessibility audit           |

The core team is based in British Columbia; remaining roles are expected to be BC-based (TBD).

### viaSport Roles (Requested)

| Role                   | Responsibilities                               |
| ---------------------- | ---------------------------------------------- |
| Project Manager        | Day-to-day coordination, decision facilitation |
| Project Sponsor        | Sign-off authority, escalation point           |
| Subject Matter Experts | UX interviews, requirements clarification      |
| UAT Testers            | Acceptance testing execution                   |
| PSO Coordinator        | PSO communication and scheduling               |

## Risks, Assumptions, and Dependencies

### Dependencies on viaSport

The proposed timeline assumes prompt collaboration from viaSport on:

| Dependency         | Timing      | Impact if Delayed                   |
| ------------------ | ----------- | ----------------------------------- |
| Legacy data access | Week 1      | Migration timeline at risk          |
| Brand assets       | Week 2      | Branding work delayed               |
| SME availability   | Weeks 1-2   | UX refinements based on assumptions |
| UAT testers        | Weeks 9-12  | UAT duration extended               |
| PSO coordination   | Weeks 15-18 | Rollout schedule impacted           |

### Assumptions

- viaSport can provide export capability or schema documentation for BCAR/BCSI
- viaSport staff are available for scheduled interviews and reviews
- No major scope changes after requirements sign-off
- PSOs are responsive to onboarding communications

### Risk Register

| Risk                       | Likelihood | Impact | Mitigation                                                    |
| -------------------------- | ---------- | ------ | ------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Legacy data access delayed | Medium     | High   | Begin migration discovery in Week 1; escalate early           |
| Data quality issues        | Medium     | Medium | Validation tooling built in; budget time in Development phase |
| viaSport SME availability  | Low        | Medium | Schedule interviews early; provide async options              |
| Scope creep                | Low        | High   | Weekly check-ins; formal change request process               |
| PSO adoption resistance    | Low        | Medium | Train-the-trainer approach; viaSport champions                |

### Timeline Commitment

This timeline represents our realistic assessment based on the working prototype and assumed collaboration. We acknowledge that external factors (data quality, legacy system access, stakeholder availability) could impact delivery.

We commit to:

- Early identification of risks and blockers
- Transparent communication if timeline adjustments become necessary
- Collaborative problem-solving to maintain schedule where possible

The working prototype significantly de-risks technical delivery. Remaining work is refinement and migration, not building from scratch.
</file>

<file path="docs/sin-rfp/response/08-appendices/final.md">
# Appendices

## Appendix A: Live Demo Access

A working prototype is available for viaSport evaluation.

**Demo URL:** [To be provided upon request]

### Test Accounts

| Persona        | Email                      | Password        | Access Level                                      |
| -------------- | -------------------------- | --------------- | ------------------------------------------------- |
| viaSport Staff | viasport-staff@example.com | testpassword123 | viaSport admin with full org access (MFA enabled) |
| PSO Admin      | pso-admin@example.com      | testpassword123 | BC Hockey organization admin                      |
| Club Reporter  | club-reporter@example.com  | testpassword123 | North Shore Club reporter                         |
| Viewer         | member@example.com         | testpassword123 | View-only access                                  |

**Note:** MFA-enabled accounts use TOTP authentication. Credentials in this draft are placeholders; actual access details will be provided with the demo environment.

### Suggested Demo Walkthrough

1. Login as viaSport Staff to see full admin capabilities
2. Explore role-based dashboard
3. Create a test form using the form builder
4. Submit data using the form
5. View submission in the analytics platform
6. Build a pivot table and export to CSV
7. Review audit logs for recent actions
8. Explore help center and guided walkthroughs

## Appendix B: System Architecture

### High-Level Architecture

```
┌─────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────┐
│                        AWS ca-central-1                         │
├─────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────┤
│                                                                 │
│  ┌──────────────┐    ┌──────────────┐    ┌──────────────┐      │
│  │  CloudFront  │───▶│    Lambda    │───▶│     RDS      │      │
│  │     CDN      │    │   (App)      │    │  PostgreSQL  │      │
│  └──────────────┘    └──────────────┘    └──────────────┘      │
│         │                   │                   │               │
│         │            ┌──────┴──────┐           │               │
│         │            │             │           │               │
│  ┌──────┴─────┐  ┌───┴───┐  ┌─────┴────┐  ┌───┴───┐          │
│  │     S3     │  │  SQS  │  │   SES    │  │  KMS  │          │
│  │  Storage   │  │ Queue │  │  Email   │  │ Keys  │          │
│  └────────────┘  └───────┘  └──────────┘  └───────┘          │
│                                                                 │
│  ┌──────────────┐    ┌──────────────┐    ┌──────────────┐      │
│  │ EventBridge  │    │  CloudWatch  │    │  GuardDuty   │      │
│  │  Scheduler   │    │  Monitoring  │    │   Threat     │      │
│  └──────────────┘    └──────────────┘    └──────────────┘      │
│                                                                 │
└─────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────┘
```

### Technology Stack

| Layer          | Technologies                                                      |
| -------------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------- |
| Frontend       | React 19, TanStack Start, TypeScript, Radix UI, Tailwind CSS      |
| Backend        | TanStack Start, Node.js, Drizzle ORM                              |
| Database       | PostgreSQL on AWS RDS                                             |
| Infrastructure | SST (infrastructure as code), AWS Lambda, CloudFront              |
| Authentication | Better Auth with TOTP MFA                                         |
| Monitoring     | AWS CloudWatch, CloudTrail                                        |

## Appendix C: Load Test Results

Load testing conducted in the sin-perf environment (latest run; date TBD).

### Data Volume

| Table                    | Rows      |
| ------------------------ | --------- |
| form_submissions         | 10.0M     |
| audit_logs               | 7.0M      |
| notifications            | 2.0M      |
| bi_query_log             | 1.0M      |
| form_submission_versions | 0.1M      |
| **Total**                | **20.1M** |

### Performance Results

| Metric              | Value | Target | Status |
| ------------------- | ----- | ------ | ------ |
| p95 Latency         | 250ms | <500ms | Pass   |
| p50 Latency         | 130ms | N/A    | Pass   |
| Concurrent Users    | 15    | N/A    | Pass   |
| Server Errors (5xx) | 0     | 0      | Pass   |

### Lighthouse Scores (latest prototype run; date TBD)

| Metric                   | Value  | Target  | Status |
| ------------------------ | ------ | ------- | ------ |
| Performance Score        | 93/100 | >80     | Pass   |
| Largest Contentful Paint | 2284ms | <2500ms | Pass   |
| Time to First Byte       | 380ms  | <500ms  | Pass   |
| Total Blocking Time      | 88ms   | <300ms  | Pass   |
| Cumulative Layout Shift  | 0      | <0.1    | Pass   |

## Appendix D: Security Summary

### Data Residency

All data hosted exclusively in AWS ca-central-1 (Montreal, Canada). No data is stored, processed, or transmitted outside Canadian jurisdiction.

### Encryption

| Scope              | Standard            |
| ------------------ | ------------------- |
| In Transit         | TLS 1.2+            |
| At Rest (Database) | AES-256 via AWS KMS |
| At Rest (Storage)  | AES-256 via AWS KMS |
| Secrets            | AWS Secrets Manager |

### Authentication

| Feature                     | Implementation                            |
| --------------------------- | ----------------------------------------- |
| Multi-Factor Authentication | TOTP with backup codes                    |
| Password Requirements       | Configurable password policy (length and complexity) |
| Session Management          | Secure cookies, configurable expiry       |
| Account Lockout             | Automatic after failed attempt threshold  |

### Authorization

| Feature                   | Implementation                              |
| ------------------------- | ------------------------------------------- |
| Role-Based Access Control | Owner, Admin, Reporter, Viewer roles        |
| Organization Scoping      | All queries scoped to user's organization   |
| Field-Level Permissions   | Sensitive fields restricted by role         |
| Step-Up Authentication    | Required for admin actions and bulk exports |

### Audit Trail

| Feature          | Implementation                                        |
| ---------------- | ----------------------------------------------------- |
| Scope            | All user actions, data changes, authentication events |
| Immutability     | Append-only storage, no modification permitted        |
| Tamper Detection | Hash chain verification                               |
| Retention        | 7 years, archived to S3 Glacier Deep Archive          |

### Compliance

- PIPEDA-aligned data handling practices
- AWS Data Processing Addendum (DPA) in place
- No sub-processors outside AWS Canada

## Appendix E: User Personas

| Persona        | Portal Access             | Key Capabilities                                                          |
| -------------- | ------------------------- | ------------------------------------------------------------------------- |
| viaSport Admin | Full platform             | Admin console, cross-org analytics, user management, system configuration |
| PSO Admin      | Organization-scoped       | Org management, reporting, analytics, user invitations                    |
| PSO Reporter   | Organization-scoped       | Form submission, file uploads, imports, limited analytics                 |
| Viewer         | Read-only                 | Dashboard viewing, report access                                          |
| Auditor        | Admin console (read-only) | Audit log access, compliance review                                       |

## Appendix F: Team Biographies

### Austin Wallace, Project Lead and Data Engineer

Austin Wallace brings 9+ years of enterprise data engineering experience combined with executive leadership in international amateur sport governance.

**Professional Experience:**

- **Clio (2024 to Present):** Data Engineer. Owns 10+ Databricks pipelines. Unlocked $1M+ in value through AI analysis. Authored company-wide AI best practices guide.
- **New Jersey Devils, NHL (2022 to 2024):** Sole Data Developer. Built end-to-end data platform processing 10 million rows per game. Developed 40+ dbt models.
- **Teck Resources (2020 to 2022):** Data Developer. Transformed legacy systems to modern testable architecture.

**Sport Sector Experience:**

- Chair, International Quidditch Association (30+ national governing bodies)
- CEO, Volunteer Media Organization (70 staff across 30 countries)
- Creator of Qdrill, training app used by Team Canada athletes

**Education:** B.Sc., University of British Columbia, Analytical Sports Management

### Will Siddal, Senior Developer

Will Siddal brings 2+ years of full-stack development experience at Teck Resources, one of Canada's largest mining companies.

**Professional Experience:**

- **Teck Resources (2022 to 2024):** Full Stack Developer. Built mission-critical reporting pipelines processing billions of rows annually. Developed internal tools using React and TypeScript. Managed cloud infrastructure on AWS using Terraform.

**Technical Skills:** Python, React, TypeScript, AWS, Terraform, PostgreSQL, Snowflake

**Education:** Simon Fraser University. Based in British Columbia.

### Security Expert (TBD)

Position in progress. Details to be provided in final submission.

### UX Designer (TBD)

Position in progress. Details to be provided in final submission.

## Appendix G: Glossary

| Term | Definition                                                      |
| ---- | --------------------------------------------------------------- |
| BCAR | British Columbia Activity Records, legacy system being replaced |
| BCSI | BC Sport Intelligence, legacy system being replaced             |
| MFA  | Multi-Factor Authentication                                     |
| PSO  | Provincial Sport Organization                                   |
| RBAC | Role-Based Access Control                                       |
| RDS  | Amazon Relational Database Service                              |
| SIN  | Strength in Numbers (project name)                              |
| SST  | Serverless Stack (infrastructure as code framework)             |
| TOTP | Time-based One-Time Password                                    |
| UAT  | User Acceptance Testing                                         |

## Appendix H: Contact Information

**Primary Contact:**

Austin Wallace
Project Lead, Austin Wallace Tech
Email: [To be provided]
Phone: [To be provided]
Location: Victoria, British Columbia

Austin Wallace Tech welcomes the opportunity to present the working prototype and discuss how Solstice can serve viaSport's Strength in Numbers initiative.
</file>

</files>
